<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Austin A. Hay</title>
    <description>This website and all its content, design and code are ©2014 Austin Hay. Questions, comments, consulting inquiry, or anything else? Shoot me an email.
</description>
    <link>http://www.austinhay.com//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.austinhay.com//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 18:59:42 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 18:59:42 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.3.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>First look at Research &amp;amp; Innovation in India</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy Labor Day to all my loved ones at home in the US. Here in India, there was no such rest for the weary.  The stream of incessant honking and motion begins at 4 in the morning and hardly settles until midnight. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday we got to take our first plunge into business in India with a visit to the General Electric John F. Welch Technology Center, a $175 million complex dedicated to GE&#39;s global research projects across its eight primary business units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The complex itself was impressive, and the people it housed, even more so: here there are 2000 research engineers and scientists, two-thirds of which have PhDs. Together they have produced over 3600 US patents and leveraged research technology to drive billions of dollars of revenue across GE&#39;s business units. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our group was privileged to see GE&#39;s materials research and materials characterization lab along with their laser technology unit. Here, scientists study, model, and synthesize the composite metals that go into the world&#39;s most impressive turbine engines. The name of this game is all about developing novel materials that operate at high stress and heat, the main environment for airplane engines. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;imageright&quot; src=&quot;/images/india-photo-2.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The laser unit worked on technologies that will characterize emissions from power plants all over the world. Pardon my butchering, but in its simplest form, a laser is passed through the gas coming off an emissions tower. The light from the laser is captured after its passed through the gas and the emissions concentrations of the gases can be discovered at a very precise level. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GE&#39;s team is working on increasing the resolution of these measurements. From a business perspective, this makes for an interesting case as GE also is one of the world&#39;s biggest power plant manufacturers. They make the plants... and they also make the technologies that help improve emissions and meet US regulations set by the EPA. The laser system being built is synced with an ammonia injection technology that helps maintain the emissions levels of harmful greenhouse gases, such as nitrous oxide, at the precise level set by the EPA. So instead of building more efficient power plants, GE has an invested interest in building profitable technologies that will keep emissions at the exact level set by the EPA -- technologies that must be bought by utility companies all over the US and the world. I wouldn&#39;t be surprised to see GE lobbying for stricter environmental standards under the EPA... its good business sense from the perspective of the technologies they offer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow we head to InfoSys and Embrace, the latter of which is a Stanford Design for Extreme Affordability founded venture. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.austinhay.com//teis%20blog/2014/09/02/India-Day-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.austinhay.com//teis%20blog/2014/09/02/India-Day-2.html</guid>
        
        <category>India</category>
        
        <category>Business</category>
        
        <category>Technology</category>
        
        <category>Stanford</category>
        
        
        <category>teis blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bangaluru: Progress and Progress Needed</title>
        <description>&lt;img class=&quot;imageright&quot; src=&quot;/images/india-photo-1.jpg&quot;&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Maybe I shouldn&#39;t have been so surprised when I got to India. There is a noticeable technology presence in this city, known for its gathering of the world&#39;s biggest players in IT services, but poverty is still woven into the fabric of Bangalore &lt;!--more--&gt; -- as is the case with so many places in India. It was eye-opening to contrast the stories I have heard of India&#39;s rapid rise with the reality of its struggle. Trash lines the streets, cars overwhelm the city&#39;s transportation system, and people are in constant motion. The massive exodus of Indian peoples from rural to urban centers, like Bangalore, has stressed the infrastructure. I have never seen so clearly the need for improved sanitation and human health. Some of the water and WASH problems noticeable here were prevalent in Cambodia when I visited last spring as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bangalore is very much a city of progress and of progress needed. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.austinhay.com//teis%20blog/2014/09/01/India-Day-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.austinhay.com//teis%20blog/2014/09/01/India-Day-1.html</guid>
        
        <category>India</category>
        
        <category>Stanford</category>
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
        
        <category>teis blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Accenture!</title>
        <description>&lt;img class=&quot;imageright&quot; src=&quot;/images/india-photo-4.jpg&quot;&gt;

On our first glance into Bangalore &lt;!--more--&gt;we came across one of Accenture&#39;s many offices located in the city. This wasn&#39;t the main headquarters, but it was still cool to see their presence is so dominantly displayed in India.



</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.austinhay.com//teis%20blog/2014/08/31/India-Accenture-sighting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.austinhay.com//teis%20blog/2014/08/31/India-Accenture-sighting.html</guid>
        
        <category>India</category>
        
        <category>Stanford</category>
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
        
        <category>teis blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TECS 2013: Takeaways</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a little bit scary to look back and see how fast two weeks went by. In such a short amount of time I was exposed to an unimaginable amount of information. Everyday was filled with observation and understanding. The coolest part of going to China is that I felt like I had travelled in time to my youth where the world still felt very mysterious. &amp;nbsp;Like the world of my childhood China was so different, so big, and so deeply complex. It was incredible to get to experience this heighted type of curiosity, wonder again, and explore the nuances of life around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blog that I&amp;rsquo;ve set up is my best attempt at reflecting on my experiences, and I think it does a good job of capturing both the arc and main inflection points of the trip. Like all things, I think its good practice to debrief and synthesize what I learned. Here&amp;rsquo;s my list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Scale: Every time I think of this word I remember my first moments in China when I looked out over a sea of skyscrapers and condominiums. There is just nothing to describe the sight. You really cannot understand issues of population or China&amp;rsquo;s increasing metropolitan growth until you see cities like Beijing or Shanghai for yourself or travel in its labyrinth of public transportation. Size and scale is not just limited to these sectors either. China has had to plan its infrastructure and development to accommodate this immense volume of people. The Three Gorges Dam put this particular aspect into perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Business in China will not be &amp;ldquo;Business as Usual&amp;rdquo;: The exploration of so many different companies in a wide variety of industries demonstrated the truly dynamic nature of business in China.&amp;nbsp; The status quo is change. Everything in China is under development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The powerpoint presentations from various executives and their numerical keypoints may fade from my memory, but the upward trends won&amp;rsquo;t. Most of these signify that China is growing in more ways that people can believe or are willing to imagine. Don&amp;rsquo;t believe everything the media claims, or what your friends tell you. Fly here and see the country for yourself. Business in China will never be the same as it is in the US or any country for that matter. It requires a willingness to understand and adapt to the changing needs of the Chinese consumer. Approach with an open mind and be sure to leave your ego at the door&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. People are still people: Fundamentally Chinese are not much different than Americans or any other person for that matter.&amp;nbsp; There are clear and undeniable differences in government, language, culture, and identity, but at base level Chinese all have basic needs and human desires. They need energy, food, water, and safety. They want good jobs, a home, a family, an education and a purpose. They seek happiness. Aren&amp;rsquo;t these the things that we all cherish so much?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I&amp;rsquo;m oversimplifying things too much, but at least for me, memories are fleeting. The best lessons are those that are simple &amp;ndash; ones that don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily tell us what to do or how to act, but change the way we think about the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In this respect, I&amp;rsquo;ve left one out one major aspect of my adventure to China. My peers. Throughout my trip I have blogged about my thoughts, but I have to attribute most of my realizations to the brilliant students who accompanied me on TECS 2013 and created an environment for these conversations to occur. The 16 or so students that came on the trip are the most intelligent, thoughtful, and articulate people I have ever met. Each and every one of them has a deeply rooted eagerness to listen, learn, reflect and share. They have taught me how to approach issues with an open but critical mind, and the importance of listening. They have showed me how to be humble, respectful, and attentive.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More importantly, everyone on the trip has maintained a unique willingness to share about their lives, to be vulnerable, to express their true thoughts and feelings and to connect.&amp;nbsp; It was easy to create heartfelt bonds with these individuals because their core values were so well aligned with those that I cherish most in others.&amp;nbsp; Through our two weeks together I have learned that they all prioritize the things that matter most in life, like self-development, and learning. They are all truly wonderful people.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite quotes in life is, &amp;ldquo;People are at the heart of everything great.&amp;rdquo; This trip once again reminds me of this truth. Cheers to TECS 2013 and to the growth we will all gain from from this experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*TECS 2013 is short for my adventures with Stanford University&#39;s TECS two week immersive business and technology program in China. Over the next two weeks I am travelling from Beijing to Shanghai and meeting with incredible businesses along the way. All posts from the program will be tagged.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.austinhay.com//tecs%20blog/2013/09/14/TECS-2013-Takeaways.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.austinhay.com//tecs%20blog/2013/09/14/TECS-2013-Takeaways.html</guid>
        
        <category>China</category>
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
        <category>TECS</category>
        
        <category>Stanford</category>
        
        <category>Top Lessons</category>
        
        
        <category>tecs blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TECS 2013: A Whole New Perspective from Foxconn</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When we first walked in to the Foxconn building I thought we must have been at the wrong place. The entrance was dark and dusty and the lights were off. Overall the place looked run-down and pretty sketchy &amp;ndash; I think this is honestly the best word to describe it! Quickly we followed an HR representative up to a small theater on the second floor where we sat through a ridiculous company introduction video. Not only was it all in Chinese, but it was so loud and the Chinese was so fast that not even our native speakers in the group could understand or translate properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;imageright&quot; src=&quot;/images/img-4595.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a short and barely discernible speech from an unnamed executive we made our way to another part of the building where we got to see the facility&amp;rsquo;s R&amp;amp;D lab. The place looked like something out of Orwell&amp;rsquo;s 1984. The square complex had white washed walls with large labeled signs. Identically dressed employees in lab coats sat at stations testing technical components while we looked on through a glass partition. It felt like we were watching lab mice &amp;ndash; but these were real people! At one point we came across a series of walls that were glazed over with a white frost. The HR representative informed us that these were Apple&amp;rsquo;s secret labs&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up, we took a short bus ride to the factory we were going to tour. I am so incredibly grateful for this experience. I wish my deepest gratitude to Stanford and Foxconn for this experience because it truly changed me. As a note, it was made very clear that no photographs were allowed. In reality, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have mattered much: The only way to understand manufacturing at a place like Foxconn is to see if for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The factory manager met us at the entrance of his plant with a welcoming smile and an informative debrief on his operation. At this particular location Foxconn manufactured a particular Apple product, which consisted of a PCB and metal casing; not the cord or anything else. I am not sure of Apple&amp;rsquo;s policy, but the last thing I want to do is get sued by my former employer or Foxconn over my writing, so I will leave this factory product unspecified.&amp;nbsp; I will say, however, that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t the iPhone (wah wah) &amp;ndash; it was just an Apple accessory item.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional parts of this product, like the plastic casing and the cord, were outsourced to other Foxconn facilities. Almost all of Foxconn&amp;rsquo;s products adhere to a similar type of vertical integration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once inside we moved through a winding maze of industrial hallways. As we passed by one I looked up and noticed nets covering us overhead about 20 feet off the ground. Shivers ran down my spine when I inquired about their purpose: they were to prevent employees from committing suicide by jumping from the higher ramparts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our group then put on yellow visitor gowns and blue footies and walked through to the main factory floor. After exiting the blast air chamber my ears were instantly ringing with the sound of automation. Before me lay hundreds of machines clicking, whirling, buzzing and beeping as they busily fulfilled unique tasks. It was a symphony of robotic melodies all chiming in harmony as raw components were transformed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The manager took us down one of the countless rows of customized machinery. He explained that each lane cost over $600,000 to create. He had a team of 500 engineers, 300 of which were automation engineers, all who had contributed to hand-building these long and dedicated production lanes. The whole thing was virtually automatic. Here and there a worker in all brown garb monitored, but the process seemed highly independent of human interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the rows we finally came across what I had initially expected &amp;ndash; a factory floor of workers hunched over small workstations manipulating small electronic pieces. The manager explained that the demand for Apple products waxed and waned with different launches. Normally, his automatic machines could churn out enough of this particular Apple product to meet demand. But sometimes he had to bring in a workforce of 2,000 employees to create the component by hand. The extra workforce helped his factory meet the world&amp;rsquo;s demand during peak season. I was rather impressed to hear that since the factory&amp;rsquo;s launch it has made major production improvements. The 2,000 employees that were brought in used to number 8,000 before the automatic lines were perfected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We continued along with our tour and eventually came to a mind-blowing part of the factory where large yellow robotic arms moved with blazing speed and razor-sharp accuracy, picking up and manipulating small electrical components. At each station an employee worked &amp;ldquo;in unison&amp;rdquo; with the machine, moving plates and loading new cartridges of material after the robot had rapidly completed its task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next area in the facility was a deformation and QA/QC machine that analyzed and sorted each product in a matter of miliseconds. As we walked along I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but stop and be amazed once again: a 5 foot tall, unmanned robotic cart with supplies and other factory items moved through the factory isle blasting pop music for the employees!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our final destination in the factory was a dark room where once again the beeping sound of robots surrounded us. This time all the lights were off. The manager was nice enough to turn them on for us so we could see the production lines, but he explained that normally the lights were kept off to conserve energy. No lights or employees were needed either since this part of production was 100% automated and perfected. They could run it day and night without any kind of supervision. I was blown away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we wrapped up our tour of Foxconn by seeing where some of the employees lived. The tall buildings oddly resembled the college dorms I lived in as an undergrad, hah. Then, I noticed again that nets surrounded all the exteriors. The manager shared that most employees at this plant were single and there was no family housing available. In their free time employees had fun events and access to on site movie theaters and computer stations with hundreds of PCs and free internet/TV. It was hard to believe that an employee could find the time or energy for much fun with such a rigorous job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;imageleft&quot; src=&quot;/images/img-4598.jpg&quot;&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I might be missing some of the details related to end of our journey because this point I was exhausted from our day and conflicted by so many different emotions. It didn&amp;rsquo;t help that the sky had become overcast and a hot rain began to fall alongside the crash of thunder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I rode back in the bus and watched the lightning I reflected. I was in shock at the ubiquitous nature of machines in the factory, but I was amazed again by the complex production machines and how they had been created to carry out the task of humans, albeit with tenfold efficiency and speed. At the same time, I felt strangely scared, confused, and melancholy by these machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The employees in these factories work 5 to 6 days a week for over 10 hours a day. While we weren&amp;rsquo;t given any indication of their salaries some data from around the web suggests that Foxconn workers make around $400 a month, so, $20 a day or $2 an hour. Most of them are just kids with an average age of 20. All of this felt so wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always imagined that our world was moving towards this Sci-Fi like state, but then to actually see it with my eyes was almost too much to handle. My heart felt for many of the factory workers after experiencing the conditions they worked in and the dull and confined lifestyle they faced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this note I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to clarify my position. The conditions I saw in the factory almost brought me to tears. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know how to react to seeing nets that prevented employees from jumping to their deaths or how to digest the fact that the humans that work in these factories are just as much slaves to supply and demand as machines are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After careful reflection I somewhat understand now that these emotions and feelings are a function of my world-view and my privileged upbringing. My heart felt for the employees because I wish I could have done something to give them all a better life. Selfishly, I wanted the production to be completely automated so that they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to endure such difficult lives. But I know this thinking is very flawed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My good friend, who is a native of China, explained that in reality if some Chinese workers didn&amp;rsquo;t have these types of jobs then they might be somewhere much worse. While the factory lifestyle seemed horrible from my perspective, for many it is quite good and actually an improvement in comparison to where they came from. As I was told, working in a factory like Foxconn can provide a real means of moving out of poor and rural living and in to bigger tiered cities. It&amp;rsquo;s a socioeconomic stepping stool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conditions that Chinese workers face is highly controversial, but I think Foxconn gets a bad rap because of its close attachment to Apple. I think this experience really showed me that China is very different from the US and the standards of what&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;fair&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; differ greatly between the nations. I am still trying to come to terms with this fact. I don&amp;rsquo;t really know what to think and I haven&amp;rsquo;t made up my mind yet, but I know that I will probably never fully understand until I explore China more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I tried to be descriptive and give an account of my tour of Foxconn from my own eyes. Beyond my feelings, one thing that really stuck with me was the manager of the factory. He seemed like such a kind and driven leader. Not only had he started on the floor like so many of his colleagues, but he also had stayed for over a decade to work up to his role. He seemed like a compassionate man and I felt that he truly cared for others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess this is just another instance in life where you can never evaluate things at face value. I wonder how the employees at Foxconn felt. I wonder how their backgrounds shaped their understanding of their position. I wonder what their hopes and dreams were. Even if the conditions at Foxconn are the norm, and even if the company is doing its best to take care of the employees while remaining profitable &amp;ndash; which is fundamentally sound business practice &amp;ndash; I still can&amp;rsquo;t shake my sadness. Are they really happy, and if not, will they ever be? These are all questions and thoughts that will take time to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*TECS 2013 is short for my adventures with Stanford University&#39;s TECS two week immersive business and technology program in China. Over the next two weeks I am travelling from Beijing to Shanghai and meeting with incredible businesses along the way. All posts from the program will be tagged.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.austinhay.com//tecs%20blog/2013/09/14/TECS-2013-A-Whole-New-Perspective-from-Foxconn.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.austinhay.com//tecs%20blog/2013/09/14/TECS-2013-A-Whole-New-Perspective-from-Foxconn.html</guid>
        
        <category>China</category>
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
        <category>TECS</category>
        
        <category>Stanford</category>
        
        <category>Engineering</category>
        
        <category>Manufacturing</category>
        
        
        <category>tecs blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TECS 2013: Touring Bao Steel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The glow of molten steel was fixating even from my vantage point 50 feet away from the mill. I could feel the heat of the bar on my face and neck.&amp;nbsp; Hissing steam burst upward as the metal slab raced through the press, compressing, stretching and cooling under surges of water and the chatter of hundreds of wheels and cranks. When the steel rolled out the other side it had transformed; it was longer and thinner, but still as bright and red as lava.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;imageleft&quot; src=&quot;/images/img-4586.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Molten steel!&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;900&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have called myself an engineer since the day I entered college, but in all my years I have never seen real manufacturing. On this trip to Bao Steel, I was galvanized by how iron ore was melted down, compressed and shaped from human machinery into a steel roll weighing over 30 tons. My education has taught me to think about things theoretically and I have only known numbers and quantity from the scope of my pencil and paper.&amp;nbsp; In this instance, however, I think I finally realized the difference between &amp;ldquo;knowing&amp;rdquo; how something is manufactured and understanding it through sight. Bao&amp;rsquo;s manufacturing just scratched the surface of this realization in comparison to Foxconn and its high tech devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This unforgettable Wednesday, started out like most of my other days in China &amp;ndash; bright and early with hot, smoggy skies. Before going to Bao Steel&amp;rsquo;s manufacturing plant we got to meet with one of the company&amp;rsquo;s Vice Presidents. This meeting opened with a super cheesey informational movie; after a few minutes I lost count of the number of times the voiceover said &amp;ldquo;synergy.&amp;rdquo; The VP, however, was a very sweet woman and gave us a lot of incredible insight into the company, which I&amp;rsquo;ll attempt to summarize here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Bao Steel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 years on Fortune 500&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; biggest crude steel producer in the world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; highest overall profits of steel producers in the world, but incredibly close behind competitor Pesco&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;130,401 employees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;23 overseas sales subsidiaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;39 marketing branches worldwide as well as 11 trading companies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$45.7 billion in revenues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;45 million tons of steel produced per year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;85% of steel produced is sold in domestic market&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 single roll of steel can weigh between 26 &amp;ndash; 40 tons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should become quite obvious right away that Bao is a massive company. Its history has been filled with mergers and acquisitions, both of which have contributed to higher consolidation at the cost of weakened efficiency. While it&amp;rsquo;s core industry is carbon steel, it also sells stainless steel and a cheaper &amp;ldquo;special&amp;rdquo; steel brand. Most of the steel it produces is segmented for use in the automotive, home appliance, engineering/machinery, and construction industries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What surprised me most from our conversation with the VP was the fact that despite its high profits, Bao and other steel manufacturers faced extremely low margins. This seemed counterintuitive considering steel is in just about everything humans produce these days &amp;ndash; how could it possibly post low margins?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the VP explained, the ore mining industry is consolidated with a few major players controlling most the market. Because of this and the fact that mining is deeply technical and requires high capital, mining companies can set steep ore prices. Meanwhile, steel manufacturing companies are widespread in China and the world. The only way to survive is often to develop better technology and undercut competitors by reducing the sales price of steel. The combination of these two phenomena has resulted in very high ore costs and very low steel prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In her closing, the VP discussed the future of Bao and how it is linked to diversifying the company&amp;rsquo;s holdings. While the list included resources development and logistics, steel processing, engineering and technology, coal chemicals, financial investment, and production services, the one item that wasn&amp;rsquo;t listed on her presentation, but was absolutely implied, was real estate. This seems to be a common theme among big companies in China with lots of capital and I just wonder what the future will hold &amp;ndash; the memory of GE Capital is still fresh for most Americans&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was at this point that our small Stanford group got a special tour of one of Bao&amp;rsquo;s hot rolling mills. I did my best to describe the experience above, but words and even pictures don&amp;rsquo;t do justice. The experience was simply incredible. Despite the grime, heat, and toxic smells, it was so magnificent to see once again how human intelligence could produce machines that literally transformed earth and metal. Seeing the steel manufacturing process was a great reminder of the power of human innovation over the last century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tour of the plant ended in about twenty minutes and soon enough we were on our way to a company that has gained a lot of media attention in the US for their manufacturing practices &amp;ndash; Foxconn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*TECS 2013 is short for my adventures with Stanford University&#39;s TECS two week immersive business and technology program in China. Over the next two weeks I am travelling from Beijing to Shanghai and meeting with incredible businesses along the way. All posts from the program will be tagged.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.austinhay.com//tecs%20blog/2013/09/12/TECS-2013-Touring-Bao-Steel.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.austinhay.com//tecs%20blog/2013/09/12/TECS-2013-Touring-Bao-Steel.html</guid>
        
        <category>China</category>
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
        <category>TECS</category>
        
        <category>Stanford</category>
        
        <category>Engineering</category>
        
        
        <category>tecs blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TECS 2013: Shanghai and a Trip to Hangzhou for Alibaba and Chint Solar</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first day in Shanghai actually took us outside of the city to visit well-known internet titan Alibaba as well as PV maker Chint Solar.&amp;nbsp; Our mode of transport, you ask? High speed rail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;imageright&quot; src=&quot;/images/img-4518.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Our train to Hanzhou.&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;700&quot;/&gt;I had never actually travelled on a rail like this in my life, so the experience was pretty incredible. &amp;nbsp;Beyond the sci-fi look and feel of the train&amp;rsquo;s exterior, the cabin was remarkably clean and the ride was smooth. Did I mention also that it travelled at 300 kilometers per hour? I wish there was a way I could send the memo to Cal Train back home in the Bay. More important, I think I have a newfound respect for California&amp;rsquo;s ambitions to construct a similar rail, despite its high cost. Vacuum transport is all the hype after Elon Musk&amp;rsquo;s alpha design, but after experiencing high speed rail for myself, I believe that it is an amazing technology that not only is clearly working well in China, but that could have practical applications in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once at Hangzhou city, our whole day consisted of visiting Alibaba and Chint Solar. At Chint we gained special access to the actual manufacturing facility and got to see PV fabrication from washing and grating the initial silicon slab to doping, cleaning, and inspecting the final cell. Much of our time at Chint consisted of understanding the solar cell manufacturing process and so there were few opportunities to jot business notes or snap photos. In reality my focus for the day lay on Alibaba, which we had visited in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, at the Stanford Center in Peking University we watched a short video on Alibaba and its founder, Jack Ma, so I think I had lofty expectations for the company. The Alibaba headquarters met these initial feelings just based on the beautiful complex that served many of its 25,000 employees. The HQ was a sprawling modern complex with green trees, sunny plazas and winding paths. It was enormous and reminded me of other HQs out of Silicon Valley&amp;hellip;but bigger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through my attention to the company&amp;rsquo;s hype and personal interest in Yahoo! I had come to understand Alibaba as something completely different than what I have discovered through the documentary at Peking and through our visit. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to break this down with greater detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, when we arrived at the HQ we were taken to a large conference room where we got the general company low-down from an HR representative. On the way up to the room I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but notice a well-used white board, a foosball table and a spread of delicious treats. Yep, this place would fit in around Mountain View.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;imageleft&quot; src=&quot;/images/img-4535.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;It was hard to bridge the language barrier with the HR representative, but I think I got all the essentials. Not surprisingly, at Alibaba, culture is king. It seems the company, like its founder, Jack, focuses on creating a fun environment and holds tightly to core values in the same way any small startup might. Most of the first hour was spent detailing how Alibaba keeps their employees happy through special awards, fun days, ceremonies and daily activities. Despite these reinforcing details, I wondered how authentic the culture actually was. It was clear that Jack Ma was a legend in the company&amp;rsquo;s founding, but had expansion and growth changed this portion of the company&amp;rsquo;s identity? It was hard to tell. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, we got a much more informative session with an Alibaba engineer from the cloud computing space. He spent most of the time explaining the technical side of Alibaba&amp;rsquo;s entrance into this the cloud and it was useful to see how these new services compared with those of other giants like Amazon and Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond this, he also explained that Alibaba was not really an e-commerce company at all, but mostly an internet one. Roughly 70% of Alibaba&amp;rsquo;s revenues come from its person-to-person website Tao Bao, of which 100% of revenues are from advertisements alone. The rest of Alibaba&amp;rsquo;s overall profits are segmented among its variety of projects, including Alibaba.com, which provides a platform for business-to-business transactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a side note, Tao Bao is essentially like eBay in the United States (&amp;hellip;actually they pushed eBay out of the China market in their rise to fame), but Tao Bao doesn&amp;rsquo;t charge transaction fees, and unlike Amazon, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t hold inventory or have any delivery infrastructure. Instead it cultivates a space where Chinese individuals can transact in a way that is more sensitive to their cultural needs than a platform like eBay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As one example of this, Tao Bao has a chat box function on their site where individuals can communicate, bargain on price and other order details, get to know each other better, and build trust before transacting. These are all fundamental aspects of Chinese culture and so the move seems natural. In the US, however, this feature on a website like eBay would drive away all its American users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this way, Alibaba really gained control of the Chinese market by tailoring its service to its people. While it seems almost obvious, this is a point that has come up across almost all the companies we have visited. It has been shocking to hear how many international companies take models that work in the US and Europe and try to simple apply them to the Chinese market, expecting it to work perfectly and to gain control of much larger volumes of customers. This simply isn&amp;rsquo;t true. If I take away anything from this trip it&amp;rsquo;s that you can never underestimate the power and magnitude of culture in business within China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future Alibaba appears poised to dominate the micro-lending and cloud-computing markets in the country. In China, the credit system appears broken and big central banks hardly lend to the country&amp;rsquo;s 1.2 billion population. This has created major opportunities for small lending and Alibaba hopes to leverage the customer data from its many platforms in order to better assess the risk of default among its borrowers and to offer the best rates possible based on this information.

	&lt;img class=&quot;imageright&quot; src=&quot;/images/img-4532.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, the cloud-computing sector posts very low profit margins and comes with extremely high upfront capital costs, but China is in need of this database infrastructure. In light of the US NSA&amp;rsquo;s requests to domestic companies like Google, Facebook and Microsoft among others, it will be especially interesting to see how the Chinese government approaches Alibaba&amp;rsquo;s new data resources in coming years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for global outlook, right now Alibaba has no incentive to enter the US market because of competition and because its core competencies are linked to the market it serves: China. In my mind Alibaba is approaching its growth carefully and with an odd sense of humility. Perhaps this is something more US companies could learn from&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s look at tech and solar further sharpened my insight into these industries and gave the whole group useful perspective on where these companies and their products are headed within the China market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow we head to Bao Steel &amp;amp; Foxconn to take a deeper look at manufacturing and to see both how steel is made and how Apple lightning connectors are assembled!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*TECS 2013 is short for my adventures with Stanford University&#39;s TECS two week immersive business and technology program in China. Over the next two weeks I am travelling from Beijing to Shanghai and meeting with incredible businesses along the way. All posts from the program will be tagged.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.austinhay.com//tecs%20blog/2013/09/12/TECS-2013-Shanghai-and-a-Trip-to-Hangzhou-for-Alibaba-and-Chint-Solar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.austinhay.com//tecs%20blog/2013/09/12/TECS-2013-Shanghai-and-a-Trip-to-Hangzhou-for-Alibaba-and-Chint-Solar.html</guid>
        
        <category>China</category>
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
        <category>TECS</category>
        
        <category>Stanford</category>
        
        <category>Tech</category>
        
        
        <category>tecs blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TECS 2013: On to Yi Chang and the Three Gorges Dam</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It was hard to say goodbye to Beijing so soon, even though my lungs vehemently disagreed. After a week in the capital we took off to Yi Chang, in the central area of China, to spend two days at the Three Gorges Dam. For the first time in over a week I got to take off for a run with some of the boys, let my legs stretch and catch a breathe of clean (er&amp;hellip;) air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dam itself was an incredible structure and a monument to the power of human creation. My inner nerd was absolutely overwhelmed. As an environmental engineer who has spent almost half a decade understanding water systems I was especially energized by the trip. Let&amp;rsquo;s just say this dam blew my damn mind!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;imageleft&quot; src=&quot;/images/img-4462.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has certainly become a recurring trend on this trip, but I honestly couldn&amp;rsquo;t wrap my head around the scale of the thing. It was over a mile across and 188 meters high. While the watermark was at a low of 150 meters, it rested at 175 meters during flood season.&amp;nbsp; On the side was a multi-layer lock system that could lift cargo vessels up and down in series, effectively allowing for augmented navigation up the Yantze River and deeper into western China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was in complete awe, but I also couldn&amp;rsquo;t believe how the surrounding area had been so widely modified by humans. There was more concrete slabwork, civil structures, infrastructure and evidence of anthropogenic impact than I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in my entire life. The whole thing was inspiring and also somewhat eerie. With a city of over a million people in eyeshot just downstream, my heart raced and mind wandered at the thought of what would happen under conditions of catastrophic dam failure. For some simple perspective there was a wall of water over 500 feet high and 1 mile across sitting in the reservoir behind the dam&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we saw the dam from a distance on the first day, we got to spend the next morning on a special access tour to see the generators. These things were monstrous machines. Each one generated over 700 MW and the dam had over 32 of them. When we went to see the control room I noticed that the water flux through the current operating turbines was roughly 17,000 cubic meters per second. This is over an order of magnitude higher than any numbers I&amp;rsquo;ve been exposed to in my fluid mechanics education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;imageright&quot; src=&quot;/images/img-4437.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the trip I revisited my thoughts on size and scale. This one dam provides only 2-3% of the energy needs of the whole country, which seems somewhat small. In reality this is a huge paradox. The dam was bigger and more powerful than anything I have ever seen in my life. Its percentage of total output may be small, but is actually equivalent to 90 billion kilowatt-hours per year (kwh/y), according to one of the dam operators. According to the US Energy Information Administration the average electricity consumption for a typical home is 11,280 kwh/y.&amp;nbsp; If we assume an average of 4 persons per home and a US population of 320 million, then a simple back of the envelope calculation shows that the same 2-3% of power supplied by the Three Gorges Dam in China could provide for 9.97% of the population in the United States (i.e. 7,978,723 homes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than ever, in the shadow of the Three Gorges I began to feel the truly incredible challenges that China faces in managing its population and fulfilling their basic needs. The environmental impacts of the dam and the relocation of 1.2 million Chinese citizens for the dam&amp;rsquo;s construction were prominent issues in my group&amp;rsquo;s discussion, but for the sake of keep this blog succinct I will leave that aside for now &amp;ndash; although they are absolutely worth further exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we flew off to Shanghai for our final week, I wondered one thing&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the decision was on me, would I have built the dam?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*TECS 2013 is short for my adventures with Stanford University&#39;s TECS two week immersive business and technology program in China. Over the next two weeks I am travelling from Beijing to Shanghai and meeting with incredible businesses along the way. All posts from the program will be tagged.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.austinhay.com//tecs%20blog/2013/09/11/TECS-2013-On-to-Yi-Chang-and-the-Three-Gorges-Dam.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.austinhay.com//tecs%20blog/2013/09/11/TECS-2013-On-to-Yi-Chang-and-the-Three-Gorges-Dam.html</guid>
        
        <category>China</category>
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
        <category>TECS</category>
        
        <category>Stanford</category>
        
        <category>Engineering</category>
        
        
        <category>tecs blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TECS 2013: Hurst Lin at DCM</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Before our final farewell to Beijing the group had the honor of sitting down for a talk with Hurst Lin from DCM China, a global VC fund that mostly engages in series A investments in technology, media and telecommunications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt compelled to write about our discussion because it was so thoughtful and authentic. Hurst Lin is best described as a casual Chinese man with a Brooklyn accent and a sense of openness and rhetoric that most often characterize a typical college student. While his list of accomplishments was long, he is probably best known outside the VC world for his role in founding the online Chinese newspaper, Sina. Throughout our talk his intelligence and humility continually impressed me and it was inspiring to get to hear from such a great VC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With such an opportunity for understanding, I wasted no time in diving in to ask questions, two of which I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to capture the essence of below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;What are the qualities you look for in good entrepreneurial leaders and good teams when selecting companies?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Lin noted first that at the core of VC investing is sensing gut feelings and using a structured approach. In relationship to China, he said, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get carried away because the economy is growing at 9-10% a year.&amp;rdquo; His approach was simple: a good company has the right timing, positioning, and team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Timing is all about figuring out if society is ready for your product or idea. It&amp;rsquo;s as simple as that. For positioning Mr. Lin was pretty straightforward, saying, &amp;ldquo;If your idea sucks then it will die, but if it&amp;rsquo;s good it will get copied and competition will form, so you have to position yourself properly from the start. A lot of this is about marketing and public perception.&amp;rdquo; The fundamental question in this case is if the product in the right position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last part of figuring out whether the team or person leading the company will succeed is really an art. As Lin clarified, &amp;ldquo;You don&amp;rsquo;t get to really know the person or team, and so you have to really make a tough decisions about how they will perform early on and with little information. That&amp;rsquo;s where operating on gut is so important.&amp;rdquo; After his words, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but think of my beloved mentor, Dr. Bennis, and his philosophy about leaders operating on instinct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What makes up a good entrepreneur?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his experience, Mr. Lin has come across two types of entrepreneurs: the ones that are super smart and the ones from humble beginnings. The first kind are rare, as he described, and are &amp;ldquo;really brilliant, but they only come around every 10 years or so if you&amp;rsquo;re lucky.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second are the ones that he usually comes across and they are smart and driven individuals, but what sets them apart is that they really have something to prove. In his own words, &amp;ldquo;These guys want to show others that they can make it. They are not necessarily super smart, but they run through walls to make things happen. You know, all of these guys have general self-confidence in themselves and they can inspire others to join their team &amp;ndash; which is really important if you&amp;rsquo;re convincing people to quit their jobs to come to a startup. They are good at understanding people and psychology and there is a type of maturity within all of them to think about others. These entrepreneurs think about how people can fit differently into an organization and make things happen.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of other questions came about, but I think the main points can be quickly recapped. Mr. Lin thought that good VC&amp;rsquo;s and good business leaders should continually re-examine if the timing of their product is still right. Between moments of thought he summarized saying, &amp;ldquo;Technology is cruel and opportunities are fleeting. Sometimes the competition can catch up faster than you think and render your idea irrelevant. So ask yourself constantly, is my product still relevant?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another salient point he made was that the heart of the entrepreneurial spirit, in his mind, comes from chasing the new idea &amp;ndash; one that can act as a substitute or change human behavior just a little bit. Beyond asking about relevancy and timing, its good to think about an idea that impacts people daily. &amp;ldquo;If you can just change the way people go about their lives a little bit then you really got a great idea,&amp;rdquo; he noted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall Hurst Lin had some amazing insight on the world of VC in China, and he also had incredible practical advice on life. His humility and honesty came across in the way he answered our questions and I left the meeting wondering how I will ever be able to master the skills, knowledge and personal qualities that make people like him so great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we wrapped up he offered some final advice to us all: &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t take yourself too seriously.&amp;rdquo; The words really resonated, but like so many other things in life, it&amp;rsquo;s always easier said than done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*TECS 2013 is short for my adventures with Stanford University&#39;s TECS two week immersive business and technology program in China. Over the next two weeks I am travelling from Beijing to Shanghai and meeting with incredible businesses along the way. All posts from the program will be tagged.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.austinhay.com//tecs%20blog/2013/09/10/TECS-2013-Hurst-Lin-at-DCM.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.austinhay.com//tecs%20blog/2013/09/10/TECS-2013-Hurst-Lin-at-DCM.html</guid>
        
        <category>China</category>
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
        <category>TECS</category>
        
        <category>Stanford</category>
        
        <category>Venture Capital</category>
        
        
        <category>tecs blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TECS 2013: More on Scale from a Cultural Perspective</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If my first drive through Beijing wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough to convince me of China&amp;rsquo;s remarkable relationship with size, then the Great Wall certainly was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In between our visits on Thursday and Friday our group was lucky enough to squeeze in a few hours at the Great Wall, Tiananmen Square, and the Forbidden City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of these historic monuments was physically overwhelming. On Friday we walked to Tiananmen Square and it took us over 10 minutes just to walk to the center of it. It was truly massive. There were thousands of people surrounding the historic centerpiece and many more near Mao&amp;rsquo;s resting place. I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t believe this space could fit over 1,000,000 people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everywhere were huge pictures of Mao as well and at first I was inclined to react with feelings of fear and defensiveness, but I tried to put myself in the shoes of the Chinese. While I don&amp;rsquo;t support Communism, the legacy of Mao, of the blood tied to Tiananmen, I do know that national heroes leave strong impressions on identity and that matters. This point became clearer when I thought of my own attachment to country: In the US we&amp;rsquo;ve constructed monuments all over the nation to our heroes and we&amp;rsquo;ve even carved their faces into a mountainside at Mount Rushmore. By putting aside my visceral political reactions I think I was able to appreciate the space more for its ability to generate pride and identity within others. And besides, it was a pretty amazing thing to see. Hopefully I don&amp;rsquo;t get in too much trouble for saying this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After our walk through Tiananmen Square we spent the next few hours going through the Forbidden City. Again, the thing I struggled to grapple with was SCALE! The Forbidden City was truly massive. We passed through several gates just to get to the Hall of Supreme Harmony where the last emperor reigned. Behind this were several more gates and hundreds of rooms and alleyways sprawling across many acres. Whenever I visit cultural places like this I love to think of what it felt like 100 years ago to be in the space. In my mind, it&amp;rsquo;s this thought that makes these places so incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, no trip to China would be complete without a visit to the Great Wall. For us this adventure actually took place the day before, on Thursday, after our business discussion with ZTE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The part of the wall we visited was over 600 years old and was built during the Ming Dynasty. It was incredibly beautiful and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but feel overwhelmed with awe. My inner engineer and nerd wondered: &lt;em&gt;How could such a large and powerful structure been built centuries ago?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both directions the wall traced the mountain crest as far as we could see. Green canopy surrounded us and provided a stark contrast to the industrial cityscape we had just come from in Beijing. In the distance we could see parts of the forest ceiling bursting through the wall in different places creating a scene out of its time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By far, the wall is a testament to the power of human endeavor and creation.&amp;nbsp; To me, it demonstrates that together people have the ability to move mountains and shake the earth, but at significant cost&amp;hellip; the lives of millions over many centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*TECS 2013 is short for my adventures with Stanford University&#39;s TECS two week immersive business and technology program in China. Over the next two weeks I am travelling from Beijing to Shanghai and meeting with incredible businesses along the way. All posts from the program will be tagged.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.austinhay.com//tecs%20blog/2013/09/09/TECS-2013-More%20on-Scale-from-a-Cultural-Perspective.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.austinhay.com//tecs%20blog/2013/09/09/TECS-2013-More%20on-Scale-from-a-Cultural-Perspective.html</guid>
        
        <category>China</category>
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
        <category>TECS</category>
        
        <category>Stanford</category>
        
        
        <category>tecs blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
