<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Austin A. Hay</title>
    <description>AustinHay.com is a millenial blog &amp; consulting stop focused on strategy, leadership, self-developement, entrepreneurship, and rookie programming. Don&#39;t be a stranger - drop me an email to connect. Contents and code &amp;copy; 2015</description>
    <link>http://austinhay.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://austinhay.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 12:52:32 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 12:52:32 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lessons From Accenture</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was grinding through the second year of my grad programs I had no idea what I wanted to do. Strangely enough, graduate school had actually opened the possibilities for my career trajectory rather than closed doors or pushed me into a niche field. I felt empowered to pursue science, technology, business, and programming, but I didn’t know where to start. Accenture provided me with a phenomenal launchpad to figure this out. It gave me time to discover where my technical skills aligned most with business needs, and through the months that I worked there, I discovered many of the “rules of the road” for operating at Fortune 500 companies. 
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;imageleft&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogs/lessons-from-accenture-1.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a huge fan of simple rules so that’s how I’m going to break down my reflections from Accenture. The concept of &lt;a href=&quot;/pdfs/Eisenhardt-StrategyAsSimpleRules.pdf&quot;&gt;simple rules&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://profiles.stanford.edu/kathleen-eisenhardt&quot;&gt;Dr. Kathleen Eisenhardt&lt;/a&gt; is that when business gets complicated, stick to some basic guiding rules that define your strategy. I love the principle of simple rules so much that now I try to glean simple rules from all the different chapters in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, my time at Accenture felt complicated. Everyday it seemed like I was served up new lessons, some more nuanced than others. Looking back, however, I found it hard to take away concrete operating lessons – but luckily some simple rules have proved to be clarifying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;simple-rules-from-accenture&quot;&gt;Simple Rules from Accenture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;1.) It’s all about the people.&lt;/b&gt; It doesn’t get much simpler than this. Like any mega organization of its kinda, Accenture has a wide variety of people. One thing that I took away from navigating this type of ecosystem is that you have to surround yourself with the people you hope to become. Those who left the biggest impression on me were the ones that were smart, open-minded, driven, focused, thoughtful and empathetic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best people were not just the smartest either, but they were the ones who had a deep fascination and love of learning and weren’t afraid to show it. More importantly, they left their egos at the door and were willing to recognize, cherish and nourish talent when they came across it. In the future, these are the types of people I hope to surround myself by. Life is too short to spend time with others who aren’t going to push you to develop and grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageright-1&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;/personal%20development/2015/01/20/Reflections-From-SETS.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/lessons-from-accenture-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	I visited Accenture in Bangalore on a trip to India with Stanford to study business, entrepreneurship and innovation during the summer of 2014.
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2.) Don’t pick something that feels comfortable.&lt;/b&gt; This idea hit me early on when I started. After training for two weeks in Chicago at ACN’s center in St. Charles, IL, I came home hungry to dive into my first project. I was taken back, however, to find that few of the projects open fit my background, interests, or technical skills. Eager to learn and to grow, I found one that fit and ran with it. In hindsight this may not have been the best move for me personally, but from one perspective, I learned so much from immersing myself in a field that was uncomfortable – where I didn’t have all the answers or skills yet and where I was challenged to learn more. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of sitting on the bench hoping for the perfect opportunity to come along, I was swimming in a sea of analyst hurt, working my butt off, but growing from the experience. This isn’t to say this strategy is for everyone. It certainly caused some problems for me down the road when I craved a better outlet for math and analytics. But in the short run, I rapidly grew from the experience. In your career and in life, don’t be afraid to get uncomfortable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;3.) Become a strategist AND an operator, not just one or the other.&lt;/b&gt; This is another one of those “Duh” lessons, but it really gets underlooked. When I came out of school I had travelled the road of Management Consulting. The interviews with McKinsey, Bain, BCG, the case prep from Victor Cheng, the countless hours thinking about markets, their trends, and profitability problems. Everyone wanted to be in strategy and nobody wanted to be in operations because it wasn’t sexy or fun. In reality, operations proved to be more valuable and meaningful to my professional development. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Operators are those people who can take strategy and translation it into action. They are the ones with a bias for action, a hunger for process, and a mentality of “get shit done.” Strategy is fun and incredibly intellectually stimulating, but don’t let that convince you that there’s not a place in everyone’s toolbelt for operations. Be a strategist and an operator. Plan and perform. Think about tough problems and then, get your hands dirty and solve them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;4.) Challenge the status quo – understand the impact, but don’t be afraid of it.&lt;/b&gt; This is really summed up by one simple question in the words of my greatest mentor: do you care more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2010/08/true-leaders-are-also-managers/&quot;&gt;doing things right or doing the right thing?&lt;/a&gt; Not only will the answer to this question will tell you a lot about yourself, but it will paint a path to professional development. In my own life, I have always tried to be a straight-shooter and somebody who builds things for a reason. I like to know the purpose behind a process or decision and I am comfortable admitting when I’m wrong and changing things that are broken or inefficient. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a large corporation there will be many opportunities to find broken things. Good companies, good leaders, good bosses, and good people will all encourage and embrace those who call out problems with the way things are done – whether its business decisions, operations, daily processes, or even the way events are planned. But not every organization will have these people and this type of culture. A true test of professional strength and willpower will be when you decide how to handle challenging the status quo when there’s realy pushback. I’m not telling you to start a fire, but I am telling you that if you want to learn to do the right thing, this is a good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wrap-up&quot;&gt;Wrap Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day Accenture was a great place to start my career and I am unbelievably thankful to the people and mentors that encouraged me and helped me succeed. The most important part of this whole process has been reflection. Taking the time to think about the things that went well and those that didn’t has given me insight into my day-to-day professional needs as well as the areas that I have room for personal improvement. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I can recommend only one thing for those moving on to new careers it is that you take the time to digest the greatest lessons from your employer. Think about them, reflect, write them down and internalize them. When life gets complicated, keep things simple. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhay.com/personal%20development/2015/02/15/Lessons-From-Accenture.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhay.com/personal%20development/2015/02/15/Lessons-From-Accenture.html</guid>
        
        <category>Reflection</category>
        
        <category>Accenture</category>
        
        <category>Awareness</category>
        
        <category>Self development</category>
        
        <category>Life lessons</category>
        
        
        <category>personal development</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Wild Ride</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s rare that you wake up wondering to yourself…“Was that all a dream?” The week has certainly felt that way. I learned about &lt;a href=&quot;https://branch.io/&quot;&gt;Branch Metrics&lt;/a&gt; less than three weeks ago. Their product, a simple drop in SDK that finally lets app developers track, monitor and manage their users using deep linking, is going to disrupt the mobile industry. It wasn’t just their technology that took my breath away, their team of founders is one of the most thoughtful and inspiring groups of people I have ever met. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://branch.io&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;imageleft-1&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogs/wild-ride-1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In grad school at Stanford I took a number of business classes where I learned the importance in surrounding yourself by the brightest and best people you can find. The goal in achieving professional success and happiness was about doing something you’re passionate about and diving in with people who are going to challenge you and make you a better person. I absolutely found these types of great people and a real opportunity to grow at &lt;a href=&quot;http://branch.io&quot;&gt;Branch&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The added bonus of the opportunity to work for Branch is the fact that I’m going to be in a role that will truly utilize my skills and will help me grow both my business acumen and technical abilities. With a small team of 12, Branch is growing rapdily in the next few months and needs people who can manage several domains of expertise, who are comfortable with sales and business intelligence, but also who aren’t afraid of code. They need people who are willing to take risks, use data to drive business decisions, possibly &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/Am-I-set-up-for-slower-growth-if-more-experienced-execs-are-hired-above-me-at-fast-growing-company/answer/Auren-Hoffman?ref=fb&quot;&gt;fail&lt;/a&gt; along the way, but ultimately grow from the experience. More specifically, they want somebody with a technical background, business understanding, and a love of technology. When I heard this I felt it was a match made in heaven, and I couldn’t have been more excited to join.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If all this wasn’t enough to convince me, their co-founder CEO, Alex Austin  – yes, it is comically fitting that we have inverse names – left me with one honest promise: A wild ride. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve decided to join the team at Branch Metrics in Palo Alto, and close my chapter at Accenture. Check out their &lt;a href=&quot;https://branch.io/contextual-deep-links/&quot;&gt;product&lt;/a&gt;, which I also write about more in the future. I hope you will follow &amp;amp; support me in this exciting new journey!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhay.com/personal%20development/2015/02/12/A-Wild-Ride.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhay.com/personal%20development/2015/02/12/A-Wild-Ride.html</guid>
        
        <category>Branch Metrics</category>
        
        <category>Professional Development</category>
        
        <category>Reflection</category>
        
        <category>Self development</category>
        
        
        <category>personal development</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is Deep Linking?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Deep linking has been one of the most talked about trends in tech throughout the last year, but not everyone fully understands what it is and how it can transform mobile. Look no further – this is a quick guide on what you need to know about mobile deep linking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-current-landscape&quot;&gt;The Current Landscape&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;float: right; margin: 2%; padding-right: 3%; margin-top: 0;&quot; width=&quot;35%&quot; height=&quot;auto&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/188674648&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it’s best to start with the current landscape. Mobile is taking over, and deep linking is &lt;a href=&quot;http://readwrite.com/2015/01/29/deep-linking-button-urx-sdk-now-hot&quot;&gt;heating up&lt;/a&gt; alongside as it promises to revolutionize UX and the way in which apps deliver content to users. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most stories focus on the promise of deep linking to provide HTTP-like functionality for mobile apps (more on this below!). Meanwhile, companies are rapidly materializing to deliver on this potential: &lt;a href=&quot;http://branch.io&quot;&gt;Branch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.urx.com&quot;&gt;URX&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trywildcard.com/&quot;&gt;Wildcard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usebutton.com/&quot;&gt;Button&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://deeplink.me/&quot;&gt;Deeplink.me&lt;/a&gt; to name a few. These new marketing and developer-centric startups are all chasing the future of how &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/nathaniel-cahners-hindman/a-deep-link-deep-dive-urx-wildcard-button-deeplinkme-demo-the-future-of-mobile_b_6449214.html&quot;&gt;deeplinks will define the future app ecosytem and user experience&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What really are the benefits of deep linking? The technology helps app developers, marketers and users in a number of ways. Specifically, deep linking can:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageleft-1&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://branch.io&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/what-is-deep-linking-1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	Branch Metrics is one deep linking startup that is delivering on the promises of the technology. They&#39;ve built a custom SDK and API that provides a way for developers to easily integrate deep linking into their core app, and build robust referral &amp;amp; conversion platforms. 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.) Drive app install and conversion - &lt;a href=&quot;http://branch.io&quot;&gt;Branch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.urx.com&quot;&gt;URX&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usebutton.com/&quot;&gt;Button&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://deeplink.me/&quot;&gt;Deeplink.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.) Track organic growth channels, understand ad campaign impact on app numbers, and analyze K factors - only &lt;a href=&quot;http://branch.io&quot;&gt;Branch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.) Supply dedicated user information &lt;u&gt;between&lt;/u&gt; web/mobile and &lt;u&gt;through&lt;/u&gt; app install. This includes actions between apps from users - only &lt;a href=&quot;http://branch.io&quot;&gt;Branch&lt;/a&gt;, but most deep linking vendors provide UX connectivity for between-app interactions, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.urx.com&quot;&gt;URX&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usebutton.com/&quot;&gt;Button&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trywildcard.com/&quot;&gt;Wildcard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://deeplink.me/&quot;&gt;Deeplink.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.) Linking analygous to HTTP providing a seamless way to interact with apps from links - &lt;a href=&quot;http://branch.io&quot;&gt;Branch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.urx.com&quot;&gt;URX&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trywildcard.com/&quot;&gt;Wildcard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usebutton.com/&quot;&gt;Button&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://deeplink.me/&quot;&gt;Deeplink.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5.) Allow mobile apps to work together, intuitively streamlining the process for developers - all of them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;This last point is the most salient one: deep linking can allow your apps to have more exposure, higher installs and conversions, but most importantly, an easier, more intuitive integration with the mobile app ecosystem.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-a-deep-link&quot;&gt;What is a Deep Link?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good thing about the internet is that there are many great resources that already exist on this subject. I’m in favor of you reading mine, but if it doesn’t quite suit your fancy, I’d recommend checking out &lt;a href=&quot;http://sarlitt.me/what-is-app-deep-linking/&quot;&gt;this other great read&lt;/a&gt; on Deep Linking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve covered the landscape of deep linking and you have an idea of the technology’s benefits, it’s time to dive into how it works – beginning with URIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;uris-are-the-foundation-of-deep-linking&quot;&gt;URI’s are the Foundation of Deep Linking&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In programming, a URI (Uniform Resource Identifier) is just a string of characters to identify the name of a resource on a network. URIs allows users to identify and interact with the resource representation over a network using specific protocols. &lt;b&gt;The most common URI out there is the URL, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_resource_locator&quot;&gt;Uniform Resource Locator&lt;/a&gt; – or more simply, a web address.&lt;/b&gt; URIs are not not limited to just this. URIs can also be comprised of URNs (Uniform Resource Name). In practice a URN functions as a web resource’s “name” while the URL functions as its address. If you’re not sold on their differences, take a look &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/176264/whats-the-difference-between-a-uri-and-a-url&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageleft&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://sarlitt.me/what-is-app-deep-linking/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/what-is-deep-linking-2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	This simple visual from Michael Sarlitt shows the primary differences between web and native apps. Check out his full post for a developer focused intro to deep linking. 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a very high level a deep link is just a hyperlink, or a special URI that routes to a resource deeper within a site’s hierarchy. It’s a hyperlink to an indexed or searchable page on a website other than the site’s home page. Generally, a website home page is at the top page in a site’s hierarchy and any other page outside of that is considered a “deep” link. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mobiledeeplinking.org/&quot;&gt;Mobile deep linking&lt;/a&gt; is really the type of “deep linking” that you’ve heard about among conversations with app and web developers. Mobile deep liking functions conceptually in the same way as web deep linking. As we discussed, deep links on the web are direct links to resources “deeper” within a site’s hierarchy. Today the term has come to encompass the methodology of routing to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techopedia.com/definition/27568/native-mobile-app&quot;&gt;native application&lt;/a&gt; via a hyperlink. In the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nngroup.com/articles/mobile-native-apps/&quot;&gt;war between web, native and hybrid applications&lt;/a&gt;, deep linking aims to make native applications more functional, more tightly integrated with the web, easier for users to operate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, again, &lt;b&gt;a mobile deep link is just a URI that contains all the information needed to launch directly into an app or a particular location within an app instead of just launching the app home page.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;examples-of-deep-links&quot;&gt;Examples of Deep Links&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of web deep links, the underlying &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webopedia.com/TERM/H/HTTP.html&quot;&gt;HTTP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_resource_locator&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/a&gt; technologies allow for deep linking by default  – which is why you pretty much never hear the term deep linking reference anything but native app links these days. Native mobile apps, however, do not have this same underlying core technology! It requires the apps to be configured to properly handle a URI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;In this way, as a URL is an address for a website on the internet, a URI for an app on a mobile device can function the same way IF deep linking technology is built into the app.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some simple examples help demonstrate the point…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://mycoolwebsite.com&lt;/code&gt; This launches a website with the respective name on the internet! &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;twitter://&lt;/code&gt; This is the iOS URI to launch Twitter’s mobile app. Depending on what follows, this could link deep into the native app with tailored and specific content. If the user doesn’t own the app it could redirect them to the app store, or to the mobile website, or prompt the user for a choice. The possibilities are endless. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ftp://&lt;/code&gt; This launches the protocol to initiate a file transfer&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;YouTube://&lt;/code&gt; This is the iOS URI to launch YouTube’s Mobile app&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageright&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://sarlitt.me/what-is-app-deep-linking/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/what-is-deep-linking-3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	This is another awesome visual from Michael Sarlitt showing how deep links can redirect users to highly specific in-app content from any ad, but especially mobile and web ads. Check out his post on deeplinking for a more developer-focused overview. If you&#39;re interested in implementing this type of behavior check out the options up top. Currently &lt;a href=&quot;http://branch.io&quot;&gt;Branch Metrics&lt;/a&gt; seems like the best option to handle this type of action and they pass data through install as well, which opens up a whole world of possibilities for UX.
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully deep linking is starting to become more clear!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;back-to-the-point-why-mobile-deep-linking-matters&quot;&gt;Back to the Point: Why Mobile Deep Linking Matters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The greatest benefit of mobile deep linking is the fact that it allows app developers &amp;amp; their marketing teams to bring users directly into a very specific location within the app with a dedicated link. Deep linking can stop the trend of platforms losing their mobile users to the web. It can automatically detect the native experience and redirect users accordingly, just as deep links have done &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nngroup.com/articles/deep-linking-is-good-linking/&quot;&gt;for the web&lt;/a&gt;. And this is just the start. Deep linking can create a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.appsflyer.com/deep-linking-now-time-mobile-search-ads/&quot;&gt;better native search&lt;/a&gt;, increase &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.facebook.com/docs/ads-for-apps/mobile-app-ads-engagement&quot;&gt;ad sales&lt;/a&gt;, drive &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.superbcrew.com/branchmetrics-helps-you-get-all-the-data-need-for-your-customer-acquisition-strategy/&quot;&gt;app conversion and organic growth channels&lt;/a&gt;, and overall create a better UX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In turn this type of technology has the potential to increase the ad market across mobile and web, better manage download traffic, bring context to the core content of an app, drive conversions, and ultimately, index all the content on an app for a more intuitive and functional search. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’ve experienced the pains of app growth without deep linking or if you’ve just heard the term flung around at the lunch table, deep linking is worth knowing about and understanding. If &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/a16z/a16z-podcast-mobile-is-eating-the-world-and-apple-is-gobbling-fastest&quot;&gt;mobile is eating the world&lt;/a&gt; then deep linking is at the head of the table.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhay.com/coding/2015/02/06/What-is-Deep-Linking.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhay.com/coding/2015/02/06/What-is-Deep-Linking.html</guid>
        
        <category>Deep Linking</category>
        
        <category>Software</category>
        
        <category>Web-development</category>
        
        <category>Technology</category>
        
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating Ruby GEMs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Every beginner Ruby developer learns the command &lt;code&gt;gem install&lt;/code&gt; early in their career, but it doesn’t take long for most to wonder what’s going on under the hood. As I’ve started to deepen my understanding of Ruby as a programming language, I’ve also become more enamored by Ruby Gems. Following this interest, I jumped into my local Gem environment and tried to make my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-ruby-gems&quot;&gt;What Are Ruby Gems?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;imageright&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogs/rubygems-1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those unfamiliar with Ruby, I can start by defining Gems. A Ruby Gem is simply a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Package_manager&quot;&gt;package manager&lt;/a&gt; that provides three main purposes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A standard format for distributing Ruby libraries, programs and scripts. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A tool that helps manage library installation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A server for distributing these libraries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, simply put, Ruby Gems are plugin software packages that contain Ruby applications and/or libraries. Gems are a fundamental part of Ruby programming because they extend and manipulate the feature set and full functionality of Ruby applications. Most commonly, Gems are used to implement re-usable features and prevent developers from having to reinvent the wheel. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is really how it works with all code libraries. In the past, when you built an incredible script or application that completed some task you might save it for your own purposes to use in all your applications. Over time, thousands of programmers have done this, sharing their work with the world – in this case via Gems using the &lt;a href=&quot;http://guides.rubygems.org/&quot;&gt;RubyGems&lt;/a&gt; software package manager – so that instead of having to go solve every nuanced programming problem they come across, they can plug into the work of others and focus more attention on building the application at hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-do-gems-work&quot;&gt;How do Gems Work?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a high level the command &lt;code&gt;gem&lt;/code&gt; is what allows you to work with Ruby Gems from your &lt;a href=&quot;http://cli.learncodethehardway.org/book/&quot;&gt;command line&lt;/a&gt;. If it’s your first time getting started with Ruby (version &amp;gt; 1.9) you will have the RubyGems commands built in, but if not, you can always &lt;a href=&quot;https://rubygems.org/pages/download&quot;&gt;download&lt;/a&gt; and run the installer from RubyGems.org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RubyGems.org provides the best resources avaiable for using and working with Ruby Gems – this shouldn’t be surprising! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are some of the cool commands you can run from terminal when working with GEMs?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem install [ Gem library Name ]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem search [ Gem library Name ]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;irb -rpp&lt;/code&gt;: Requires a library when irb loads!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem list&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem uninstall [ Gem library name ]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ri [ Gem library name ]&lt;/code&gt;: View the documentation of the requested Gem.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem server&lt;/code&gt;: Lets you view the documentation for your installed Gems using a local host.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem fetch [ Gem library name ]&lt;/code&gt;: Let’s you audit a Gem’s contents without downloading it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem unpack [ Gem library name ]&lt;/code&gt;: After fetching, you can extract the contents from the &lt;code&gt;.gem&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This list serves as a launchpad. There are loads of other awesome &lt;a href=&quot;http://guides.rubygems.org/command-reference/&quot;&gt;Gem commands&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://guides.rubygems.org/command-reference/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/rubygems-2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you have an understanding of ruby Gems and how to work with them, it’s time to turn our attention to the main argument – how to &lt;b&gt;build&lt;/b&gt; Ruby Gems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;building-your-own-gem&quot;&gt;Building Your Own Gem&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process is actually quite simple. First I recommend checking out these two resources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://guides.rubygems.org/make-your-own-gem/&quot;&gt;Make Your Own Gem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quickleft.com/blog/engineering-lunch-series-step-by-step-guide-to-building-your-first-ruby-gem/&quot;&gt; Step-by-Step Guide to Building Gems &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing is easiest using &lt;code&gt;bundle&lt;/code&gt; as explained in the Step by Step guide. It works like this…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ gem install bundle
$ bundle gem [ Your Gem name ]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t necessarily have to run bundle in order to create a Gem. You could also use built in Gem commands. First, navigate to where you want to build your Gem in CL. Create a &lt;code&gt;.gemspec&lt;/code&gt; file using the required syntax and nomenclature. Confused? Here’s an &lt;a href=&quot;http://guides.rubygems.org/specification-reference/&quot;&gt;example&lt;/a&gt;. And if that’s not enough, here’s one of my .gemspec files so that you understand what it might look like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;imageright&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogs/rubygems-3.png&quot; href=&quot;http://guides.rubygems.org/command-reference/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you’ve made your &lt;code&gt;.gemspec&lt;/code&gt; file you can run &lt;code&gt;gem build [ Your gem name].gemspec&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gem will automatically get built for you with all the correct directories, subdirectories and required files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, you could just start from scratch by navigating to the directory where you want to build your Gem and creating the following files / sub-directories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Subdirectories:&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;code&gt;lib&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code&gt;spec&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Files:&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;code&gt;.gitignore&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code&gt;.travis.yml&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code&gt;[ GEM NAME ].gemspec&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Gemfile&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code&gt;LICENSE.txt&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Rakefile&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code&gt;GEMLOCK&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;gem-visualization&quot;&gt;Gem Visualization&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above list serves as the architecture for your Gem, but you still might be wondering what the tree structure of a Gem looks like. If you ran the previous &lt;code&gt;bundle&lt;/code&gt; commands (or built it yourself) and named your Gem “freewill”, per &lt;a href=&quot;http://guides.rubygems.org/what-is-a-gem/&quot;&gt;this example&lt;/a&gt;, this is what you would have created automatically. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/rubygems-4.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;building-with-test-driven-development&quot;&gt;Building with Test Driven Development&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this point you will want to build your Gem using &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Test-driven_development&quot;&gt;Test-Driven Development&lt;/a&gt; (TDD). Most people use &lt;a href=&quot;http://rspec.info/&quot;&gt;RSpec&lt;/a&gt; to do so. In TTD you’ll want to first add rspec to your Gem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Gem:Specification.new do |spec|
   spec.add_development_dependency &#39;rspec&#39;
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can create a &lt;code&gt;spec&lt;/code&gt; sub-directory within your Gem home directory. And add &lt;code&gt;spec&lt;/code&gt; helper and Gem test files. Here’s an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ mkdir spec
$ cd spec
$ touch [ Gem Name ]_spec.rb
$ touch spec_helper.rb
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using TTD and Rspec is outside of the scope of this article, but you you can add all your tests into these newly created ruby files. Learn more about that &lt;a href=&quot;http://rspec.info/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deploying-your-gem&quot;&gt;Deploying Your Gem&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After many hours of building your awesome Gem you’ll probably get to the point where you’re interested in publishing. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://guides.rubygems.org/publishing/&quot;&gt;process&lt;/a&gt; is also very simple. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best and easiest way to spread the gospel of your Gem to other Ruby developers (and easily use it in all your projects with a simple &lt;code&gt;gem install&lt;/code&gt; command…) is to publish to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rubygems.org&quot;&gt;RubyGems.org&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rubygems.org/sign_up&quot;&gt;Signup&lt;/a&gt; on their website and then push your Gem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ gem push [ Your Gem ].gem
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will be prompted for login information, but RubyGems will save your credentials to &lt;code&gt;~/.gem/credentials&lt;/code&gt; from the command line so that you won’t have to do it everytime you push.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wrap-up&quot;&gt;Wrap Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, Ruby Gems are a fundamental aspect of coding in Ruby. It doesn’t take much time to start implementing them in your &lt;code&gt;.rb&lt;/code&gt; files with the &lt;code&gt;require&lt;/code&gt; tag, but creating your own Gem is a bit complicated. Hopefully this short intro gives you a first look and provides the resources needed to dive further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have more time, I highly recommend learning to build Ruby Gems by exploring those Gems that have already been created. You can do this by navigating to the directory where your Gems are stored. Use the following in CL:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ gem environment
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using your favorite text editor, open up some existing Gems – or Gems that you use frequently – and see how they are built. Compare the architecture you see there to the one I’ve described. Go one step further and see how their tests are established and how their primary &lt;code&gt;.rb&lt;/code&gt; file works. You will learn an extraordinary amount by immersing yourself in existing Gems! Happy coding!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhay.com/coding/2015/02/01/Creating-GEMs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhay.com/coding/2015/02/01/Creating-GEMs.html</guid>
        
        <category>Ruby</category>
        
        <category>GEM</category>
        
        <category>Software</category>
        
        <category>Web-development</category>
        
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bitcoining with Ruby</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With all the news about bitcoin these days, it’s hard not to think about working with the developer platforms that power access to the currency. &lt;a href=&quot;http://coinbase.com&quot;&gt;Coinbase&lt;/a&gt; is one well known bitcoin platform that totally rocks and recently &lt;a href=&quot;http://dealbook.nytimes.com/2015/01/20/coinbase-a-bitcoin-start-up-raises-75-million-in-vote-of-confidence/?_r=0&quot;&gt;raised $75M&lt;/a&gt; in funding to grow their base. From my perspective this looks like a great starting point to learn how to plug into a bitcoin developer API – and that’s exactly what I explored earlier this week.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;imageleft&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogs/coinbase-with-ruby-4.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full code repository from this post can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AustinHay/coinbase-api-basics&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; – along with my other motives for exploring the Coinbase API, but I’ll start by demonstrating the end product of using the Coinbase Ruby wrapped API. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had used Bitcoin across other apps and had a Bitcoin account before, but I’d never really traded the currency much. I certainly hadn’t dove into the backend of how a bitcoin API functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin’s API is incredibly straightforward and easy to use. What do I love most? It’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coinbase/coinbase-ruby&quot;&gt;well supported with Ruby&lt;/a&gt;! This made my life a lot easier as this (Ruby) is where my comfort zone is developing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me walk you through some of the basic take-aways I had from exposing myself to Coinbase’s API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;background-on-coinbase-api&quot;&gt;Background on Coinbase API&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you should check out the API docs for yourself. Go &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coinbase.com/docs/api/overview&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to get started. At a high level, the Coinbase API is a simple REST API that supports all of the core bitcoin operations, such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buying / selling &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sending / Requsting via email / BTC address&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exchanging to local currency&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accept payments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Storing securely&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wallet creation &amp;amp; management&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Access raw network data, including blocks, transactions and addresses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manage micro-transactions and recurring payments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;working-with-ruby&quot;&gt;Working with Ruby&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;imageright&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogs/coinbase-with-ruby-1.png&quot; /&gt;
* &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coinbase.com/&quot;&gt;Signup&lt;/a&gt; for a Coinbase account.
* &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coinbase.com/settings/api&quot;&gt;Enable an API Key&lt;/a&gt; on your CoinBase Account&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get your machine started with:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem install coinbase&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hmachttpenwikipediaorgwikihash-basedmessageauthenticationcode-authentication&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hash-based_message_authentication_code&quot;&gt;HMAC&lt;/a&gt; Authentication:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, HMAC is wicked cool and in my humble view a bit complicated to wrap your head around at first. A great deep dive on the content is on &lt;a href=&quot;http://security.stackexchange.com/questions/20129/how-when-do-i-use-hmac&quot;&gt;security exchange&lt;/a&gt; – which is definitely worht the time if you have it. Coinbase &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coinbase.com/docs/api/authentication&quot;&gt;talks security&lt;/a&gt; in their API docs as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the purposes of this simple tutorial, however, you just need to know that in order to clear HMAC auth you’ll need to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coinbase.com/settings/api&quot;&gt;go to your account settings&lt;/a&gt; and setup an API Key. If you’re unsure which type of key to use, here’s a quick reference:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/coinbase-with-ruby-2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can start using some Ruby to play with Coinbase. First, create a client instance and pass it the API key and Secret from your Coinbase account. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;coinbase = Coinbase::Client.new(ENV[&#39;COINBASE_API_KEY&#39;], ENV[&#39;COINBASE_API_SECRET&#39;])
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure not to share your API Key or Secret with ANYONE! The reason we use environment variables (and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ruby-doc.org/core-2.2.0/ENV.html&quot;&gt;Ruby accessor&lt;/a&gt;) instead of hard coding it in is because you could expose your account to mailicious users. It’s generally a good security practice to hide your API Keys – read more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coinbase.com/docs/api/authentication#security&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In practice for most Ruby apps or lightweight apps (ie Sinatra) this would be easy to implement by adding the Key and Secret to your config YAML file. Make sure to &lt;code&gt;.gitignore&lt;/code&gt; this file so you don’t end up pushing it to your public repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what your process flow for that might look like if you’re operating from CL:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd [your-coinbase-script-directory]
git init
touch config.yaml
echo &quot;COINBASE_API_KEY: abcdefg12345&quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; config.yaml
echo &quot;COINBASE_API_SECRET: abcdefg12345abcdefg12345&quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; config.yaml
touch .gitignore
echo &quot;config.yaml&quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; .gitignore
git add .
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can store your variables locally and load them up in your script. Here’s a snippet from the script I’ve been playing with to give you a sense of how this might work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#!/usr/bin/env ruby

require &#39;yaml&#39;
require &#39;coinbase&#39;

secrets = YAML::load(File.open(&#39;data.yml&#39;))

# Test to make sure your secrets are working
# puts secrets[&#39;COINBASE_API_KEY&#39;]
# puts secrets[&#39;COINBASE_API_SECRET&#39;]

coinbase = Coinbase::Client.new(secrets[&#39;COINBASE_API_KEY&#39;], secrets[&#39;COINBASE_API_SECRET&#39;])
balance = coinbase.balance.to_s
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the implementation is very basic and super powerful. There are tons of other options that you can implement on the Coinbase Github &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coinbase/coinbase-ruby&quot;&gt;Repo&lt;/a&gt; alongside great resource materials as well. I cannot recommend enough the utility of this page! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;coinbase-tip-implementation&quot;&gt;Coinbase Tip Implementation:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if all this API implementation stuff is too much to handle and you just want a super easy and quick solution to get bitcoin on your personal website, then look no further. Coinbase has an elegant solution for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coinbase.com/tip#tip-creation-form&quot;&gt;Coinbase Tip&lt;/a&gt; page and enter your custom URL. Coinbase does the dirty work and spits out an integrated JS script for drag and drop functionality in most major websites. This is very similar to the drag and drop functionality of most major web-apps: such as instagram, twitter, strava, facebook, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a sample of what the code might look like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;cb-tip-button&quot; data-content-location=&quot;http://austinhay.com&quot; data-href=&quot;//www.coinbase.com/tip_buttons/show_tip&quot; data-to-user-id=&quot;54b2fbcb0c639c8be50000c5&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;!function(d,s,id) {var js,cjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],e=d.getElementById(id);if(e){return;}js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=&quot;https://www.coinbase.com/assets/tips.js&quot;;cjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,cjs);}(document, &#39;script&#39;, &#39;coinbase-tips&#39;);&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;issues&quot;&gt;Issues:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I did find some issues with Coinbase’s API docs. I’ll point out a few, but this is good to know in case you get stuck while working with their developer set:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.) Broken/defunct link referenced as, “api reference,” on the Github Coinbase-Ruby page. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dead link is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://coinbase.com/api/doc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Possible new links could be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coinbase.com/docs/api/overview&quot;&gt;https://www.coinbase.com/docs/api/overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.coinbase.com/api&quot;&gt;https://developers.coinbase.com/api&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.) Broken/defunct links for the Python, Ruby and Java examples in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coinbase.com/docs/api/authentication#&quot;&gt;API docs&lt;/a&gt; for authentication:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/coinbase-with-ruby-3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After these two, I started hitting some other dead, redirect links. It would be good for them to crawl their API docs and check for these, but otherwise this was a solid showing and I thought everything was very well wwritten and intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;need-more&quot;&gt;Need More?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond personal implementation the next accomplishment is merchant setup. There are some great &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coinbase.com/docs/merchant_tools/examples&quot;&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt; with some well known names that can demonstrate OAuth and merchant setup using the API. There’s even an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coinbase.com/docs/api/oauth_tutorial&quot;&gt;OAuth tutorial&lt;/a&gt;! If you needed more, this would be the best place to start.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhay.com/coding/2015/01/26/Bitcoining-with-Ruby.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhay.com/coding/2015/01/26/Bitcoining-with-Ruby.html</guid>
        
        <category>Bitcoin</category>
        
        <category>Ruby</category>
        
        <category>Software</category>
        
        <category>Coinbase</category>
        
        <category>API</category>
        
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scripting Your Way to Productivity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I set out to learn to code last year, I had no real understanding of how simple web-development languages might increase my productivity and efficiency in my daily routine. In all honesty, I was just eager to learn more of what was going on under the hood of my computer. But as an engineer and somebody with a background and love of technology, I actually believed that I was maxing out my returns on my existing computer knowledge. &lt;b&gt;In hindsight, I could not have been more wrong. Learning to code over the last several months has empowered me not only to develop a new career trajectory, but to excel as a business operator. It’s allowed me to do things faster, better, and more efficiently.&lt;/b&gt; 
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=scripting&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;imageright&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogs/scripting-productivity-4.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, coding has taken many forms, but one element – &lt;b&gt;scripting&lt;/b&gt; – has proven to be the gold-mine of skill-building. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scripting_language&quot;&gt;Scripting&lt;/a&gt; is fundamentally the process of automating and executing tasks that, alternatively, would have to be performed by hand. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of how many things you do manually every day. Setting up those meeting notes? Scheduling those emails? Transferring small tidbits of data from one excel sheet to another. Sometimes these are essential details of any role. But wouldn’t it be great to invest some additional time upfront to never have to worry about it again? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scripting is awesome because it allows you to do this! It lets you take new or existing knowledge of any computer language and build robust tasks that automate the things you spend countless minutes (or hours) on every week. What’s more important is that &lt;b&gt; scripting is not just a great tool for coders – it’s an essential skill for business people, students, blue-collars, white-collars, artists, professors, parents and anyone else who uses a computer to do their daily work.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eweek.com/c/a/Enterprise-Applications/How-to-Save-Time-and-Money-using-Scripting-Technology&quot;&gt;high-level biz ops tasks&lt;/a&gt; can be identified easily. But really, you should be thinking about how learning computer programming – and therein investing many upfront hours – can actually increase your performance at work, improve your time flexibility, and cut away the mundane tasks that you might encounter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To further this picture, let me give you some examples of how I have used scripting to improve my work flow and become a more efficient operator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bcase-1-personal-use----a-simple-script-to-randomly-select-and-move-photosb&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Case 1: Personal Use – A Simple Script to Randomly Select and Move Photos&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;imageright&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogs/scripting-productivity-1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like this script after reading through it and want to implement the code, find it &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AustinHay/jekyll_website/blob/master/assets/tasks/load.rake&quot;&gt;here on Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first case is a personal script I wrote to help randomly select background photos from a huge repository and move them to my blog’s image asset repository. Why did I need to develop a script for this? Because I have a huge database of over 1000 photos that I want to cycle through for my blog. Everytime I pushed changes to my website, I would go through and stare at all 1000+ photos in a tiny folder on my Mac. The chances of me changing these photos intelligently are quite low. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after doing this task by hand for a while, I finally decided to build a small script that operated in this way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.) Go to my background-images repository.
2.) Fetch 10 unique, random, non-repeating images.
3.) Rename them to fit my CSS tags.
4.) Copy and move them to my website image assets folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick snippet of what the script ended up looking like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/scripting-productivity-2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The script was actually very easy to build. You see, the thing about high-level languages today is that there are incredible libraries that support the work you’re doing. For Ruby, there is a &lt;code&gt;fileutils gem&lt;/code&gt; that allows you to operate command line functions from a script. You can even add &lt;code&gt;chmod&lt;/code&gt; characterization and run it as a &lt;code&gt;shell script&lt;/code&gt;. In essence, this allows you to create double-click functions that perform WHATEVER YOU WANT!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, you still don’t think this is cool? Let’s check out another case study in my professional work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bcase-2-professional-use----another-simple-script-to-create-on-demand-meeting-note-templatesb&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Case 2: Professional Use – Another Simple Script to Create On-Demand Meeting Note Templates&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like this script as well? It’s also on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AustinHay/ACN-Meeting-Notes-Generator&quot;&gt;my Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of any analyst role is to document legit meeting notes when working with your clients. I am constantly meeting with the client team members to gather data and insights about the our project scope and deliverables. In the beginning, I started every meeting the same way – prep five minutes before hand by opening up last week’s notes, finding the information I needed to carry over, redesigning the template, inputting the relevant date, time and attendees. Sometimes this simple process could take 10 minutes and I’d be strambling in the first few minutes of my meeting to get settled. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more I thought about it, the more I realized that this did NOT have to be this way. Instead of sacrificing more time on the front end, I could use a simple script to automate this process everytime. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick look at the script:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/scripting-productivity-3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bscripting-roib&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Scripting ROI&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you’ve seen the power of scripts, it is necessary to talk value. &lt;b&gt;What is the true ROI on scripting?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can use both our previous cases. In Case # 1 - moving photos randomly from one folder to another with unique selecting - took me about 8 minutes to do. This sounds crazy, but you have to remember that the complete process involved navigating to the folder, grabbing 10 “randomly” out of thousands and then copying, pasting and renaming them all. If I completed this task 1 time per week for every week of the year, this is roughly 7 hours! Now, all I have to do is go to command line and type &lt;code&gt;rake load:photos&lt;/code&gt; and those 8 minutes are mine again. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, for Case # 2 my – prepping my meeting notes – we can generalize and say that I save 5 minutes per meeting using my script. If I have 10 meetings per week, this is roughly an hour every work week I’m saving – and it means I don’t have to spend that hour mindlessly preparing a Word Doc. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bstart-scriptingb&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Start Scripting&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you’re sold on the power of scripting to help you unlock higher producivity, more time, and the end of mindless taks. If you’re wondering where to start, do not fear, I’ve included another great resource list below to help you get started. The fundamentals of scripting start on command line. From there, jump into any language you’d like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;biintro-to-bashib&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Intro to BASH:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cli.learncodethehardway.org/book/&quot;&gt;Command Line Crash Course&lt;/a&gt; Note: This is actually the site where I first learned to code. This guy does an INCREDIBLE job of teaching a lot of fundamental programming skills. If you’re looking to start somewhere, this site is the place.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tldp.org/HOWTO/Bash-Prog-Intro-HOWTO.html#toc1&quot;&gt;Bash Basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tldp.org/LDP/Bash-Beginners-Guide/html/ß&quot;&gt;Bash for Beginners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codecoffee.com/tipsforlinux/articles2/043.html&quot;&gt;More Bash!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, I hope this reading gave you a look into developing a coder mindset. In the future rememeber to think on your daily life and ask yourself:  Is there something I do frequently, every day or every week that I should automate?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The power starts with YOU.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhay.com/coding/2015/01/24/Scripting-Your-Way-to-Productivity.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhay.com/coding/2015/01/24/Scripting-Your-Way-to-Productivity.html</guid>
        
        <category>Scripting</category>
        
        <category>Web-development</category>
        
        <category>Software</category>
        
        <category>Business Productivity</category>
        
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reflections from Two Summers with Stanford&#39;s Technology &amp; Entpreneurship Programs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was lucky enough to take part in both inaugural Summer Engineering and Technology Study Tours, in the summer of 2013 and 2014. As a two term veteran of the nascent Stanford program, I feel especially proud to have participated in the journey and to have come away with life-long friends, inspiring mentors, and diverse global lessons. In fact, my trip to India this last summer to study business, technology and entrepreneurship with SETS was single-handedly one of the most influential experiences I had during my time at Stanford University.
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;imageright&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogs/teis/india-photo-12.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I walked away from my first Stanford trip to China in 2013, I wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;http://austinhay.com/tecs%20blog/2013/09/14/TECS-2013-Takeaways.html&quot;&gt;short piece&lt;/a&gt; about some of the salient things I learned. Now, reflecting on my second adventure, this time to India, I’ve realized that SETS was much more a journey than a singular trip – one filled with foundational learning in technology, business, culture, global communications and, most importantly, deep personal growth. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did I get out of the experience, exactly? Why was SETS so life-changing? Well, for a number of reasons. Here’s just a few…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is no substitute for hands on experience in developing countries. You gain intangible understanding of people and human nature by throwing yourself into a place half a world away. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The relationships you make with your peers on the trip are invaluable – I found some of my closest friends at Stanford who will remain with me for the rest of my life. More importantly, you bond not only through cultural immersion, but through intense intellectual discovery. Nothing quite compares to friends made in this context. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You get to meet real entrepeneurs and executives who speak about the business landscape with genuine perspective. This goes far beyond anything that can be learned in a textbook or a seminar. These leaders have lived and breathed business in the developing world and have powerful stories to share that can help guide in making impact. These interactions also serve to connect students with lasting mentors and opportunities to return and both live &amp;amp; work in Asia. If you don’t believe me, just take a look at some of the great companies we got to visit last year:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;General Electric Global Research&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;InfoSys Consulting&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://embraceglobal.org/&quot;&gt;Embrace&lt;/a&gt; – which was actually a product of &lt;a href=&quot;http://extreme.stanford.edu&quot;&gt;Stanford Extreme&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Microsoft Ventures &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Zipdial – recently &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.twitter.com/2015/bringing-twitter-to-more-people-around-the-world&quot;&gt;acquired&lt;/a&gt; by Twitter for $40M.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;NASSCOM&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Philips Lighting Innovation Center&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;IIT Delhi&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://uidai.gov.in/auth.html&quot;&gt;The Unique Authentication Authority of India&lt;/a&gt; – home of the incredible Aadhaar authentication process.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Times Internet Division&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The challenges of developing countries comes into focus: Poverty, infrastructure, education, a risiing middle class, political strife, and growing civil rights for women, minorities, and the underserved. It was difficult to walk through the crowded streets of cities like Beijing and Bangalore, feel the development occuring, and not take notice of the stark contrasts.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I came back from China, I felt changed. Then, again over a year later, going to India with the same program and the same goals, I also came away feeling like a different person than when I had taken off from California.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width: 100%, margin: auto&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;year-in-review-photos&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogs/teis/india-photo-9.jpg&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img class=&quot;year-in-review-photos&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogs/2014-year-in-review/friends_india_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;	

	&lt;img class=&quot;year-in-review-photos&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogs/teis/india-photo-11.jpg&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img class=&quot;year-in-review-photos&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogs/teis/india-photo-8.jpg&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img class=&quot;year-in-review-photos&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogs/teis/india-photo-6.jpg&quot; /&gt;	

	&lt;img class=&quot;year-in-review-photos&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogs/teis/india-photo-5.jpg&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My experiences with SETS gave me an unwavering sense of global perspective – I really felt like I had tasted the nuances of life in different countries where socio-economic challenges are so greatly at odds with those of the US. The interactions with local business leaders demonstrated how entrpreneurship functions in a context outside of Silicon Valley and I feel better prepared than ever to pursue a career beyond US borders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I realized how similar I was to so many others around the world. I fell in love with countries of the East, the opportunities that exist there, and the people that make these locations so incredible. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a Stanford student you can and should become involved in this once-in-a-lifetime opportunity. This might be the best chance you’ll ever get to explore an incredible side of the world. Learn more &lt;a href=&quot;http://engineering.stanford.edu/portals/student/global-engineering-programs/sets&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhay.com/personal%20development/2015/01/20/Reflections-From-SETS.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhay.com/personal%20development/2015/01/20/Reflections-From-SETS.html</guid>
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
        <category>Reflections</category>
        
        <category>Global Perspective</category>
        
        <category>TEIS</category>
        
        <category>TECS</category>
        
        <category>SETS</category>
        
        <category>India</category>
        
        <category>China</category>
        
        <category>Stanford</category>
        
        
        <category>personal development</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>For My Friends: A Millenial Guide to Finance</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;
So you&#39;ve just graduated from college (or grad school). You have $40,000 in loans and don&#39;t know whether it&#39;s better to pay it now or in small increments so that you can begin the coveted journey of &#39;saving&#39;. You have limited investment knowledge, but know that 2015 is the year you need to change. Stock basics? Sure, you own 15 shares of a company or two. Bank account, brokerage account, trading account? Yup. You have them, but hardly use them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this sounds even remotely familiar then you’ve come to the right place. Personal finance is not really that scary. &lt;b&gt;Like most things, however, it takes time, practice, committment, and a bit of a learning curve to overcome.&lt;/b&gt; The hard truth is that developing a knowledge &amp;amp; understanding of how finance works in your own personal context is one of the most important things you can do to set yourself up for long-term success. You’ve heard this before, but honestly, you should not put this off; start learning right now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Basics&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the conversations I’ve had about investing with my friends, the question I always get is, &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Where do I even start?”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Easy. Start by reading “&lt;a href=&quot;http://jasonkelly.com/books/smi-html/&quot;&gt;The Neatest Little Guide to Stock Market Investing&lt;/a&gt;” by Jason Kelly. It’s one of the best books I have ever read on the basics of the stock market and will help get you up to speed with the jargon needed to manage your finances. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;imageleft&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogs/millenial-guide-to-finance-2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve taken a swing at your first finance read, you should know that reading and learning is the only way to become truly proficient with personal finance. You should (try) to read all of these in your 20’s:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.investopedia.com/articles/07/ben_graham.asp&quot;&gt;Intelligent Investor&lt;/a&gt; by Benjamin Graham&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Market_Wizards&quot;&gt;Market Wizards&lt;/a&gt; by Jack D. Schwager&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/The-Essays-Warren-Buffett-Corporate/dp/1611634091&quot;&gt;The Essays of Warren Buffett: Lessons For Corporate America&lt;/a&gt;” by Warren Buffett, or you can find the PDF &lt;a href=&quot;/pdfs/The.Essays.of.Warren.Buffett.pdf&quot;&gt;free&lt;/a&gt; online almost anywhere…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/books/2003/feb/08/society&quot;&gt;Free Lunch&lt;/a&gt; by David Smith&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rich Dad, Poor Dad by Robert Kiyosaki&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beating the Street by Peter Lynch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Investment Science by David Luenberger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Corporate Finance by Berk DeMarzo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.investopedia.com/&quot;&gt;Investopedia&lt;/a&gt;is also a great online resource to reference when you get stuck, or if you’re just curious.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond this, it helps to develop a better understanding of financial terms and how they apply to long-term investing. Ultimately, you want to know as much as you can so that you can protect yourself from getting in trouble. Equally important is knowledge of what to do with your money as it starts to grow. I’m a big believer in people – you can and will make more money in time if you dedicate yourself to improving by learning!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This resource list is usually enough to get people started, but I get a lot of common questions. Here are some of the top ones that are worth exploring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;b&gt;What are &quot;securities&quot;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are not home protection systems. They refer to the different types of financial objects that exist in the market. Some are very &lt;b&gt;risk-averse&lt;/b&gt; – meaning you’re not going to expose yourself and your portfolio to a huge catastrophy if the market goes up in flames. Other securities are very &lt;b&gt;risky&lt;/b&gt;. If you like Vegas, anxiety, sleepless nights, and roller coasters, then you’re at home here. Here are examples of different securities by type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Risky Securities:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stocks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Options&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Futures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mutual Funds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Indexes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Risk-Averse Securities:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Government Bonds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Corporate Bonds (Still kinda risky, since a corporation &lt;i&gt;can&lt;/i&gt; default)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plane Jane Interest (ie interest paid from keeping cash in a savings account)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;b&gt;Is a retirement account different from a savings account?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;imageright&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogs/millenial-guide-to-finance-1.png&quot; /&gt;
Yes, ABSOLUTELY. Generally speaking a savings account – the most common way that young individuals save – is held with a bank. You deposit cash into your account and the bank gives you interest on the money held every month – usually to an abysmally low tune of 0.5%. A retirement account is a different beast of its own. It is usually managed and operated by a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ibtimes.com/top-five-online-brokerage-firms-according-investors-business-daily-1493704&quot;&gt;brokerage firm&lt;/a&gt; and can take many &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.irs.gov/Retirement-Plans/Plan-Sponsor/Types-of-Retirement-Plans-1&quot;&gt;different forms&lt;/a&gt; such as…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Individual Retirement Arrangement (IRA)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roth IRA&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;401(k)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;401(b)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Savings Incentive Match Plans for Employees (SIMPLE IRA)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simplified Employee Pension (SEP IRA)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And many &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.irs.gov/Retirement-Plans/Plan-Sponsor/Types-of-Retirement-Plans-1&quot;&gt;more&lt;/a&gt;…	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s really important to take away from all of these different options is that each one has different rules associated with it. For instance, there’s a $5,500 limit per year on ROTH IRA accounts. That means you can’t deposit more than this amount without violating IRS tax rules. And you can’t even hold this type of account if you make over $115,000 per year. These types of rules apply to all different types of brokerage and retirement accounts. As you start to invest and put your money down, make sure to read and understand your account types. This will save you tons of time on the back-end when you pay taxes and will also help you grow your financial literacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;b&gt;All this information was super cool -- but what do &lt;u&gt;you&lt;/u&gt; do?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally speaking, I invest across a few different platforms and in a few different accounts. I have two bank accounts where I hold checking and savings accounts to meet my daily needs. For investing and retirement I have Indvidual Investing, IRA, and ROTH IRA accounts with a brokerage firm which I won’t disclose for personal security reasons. One of my employers also gives me a 403(b). For fun I trade options and stocks on the side with two separate smaller trading firms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;imageleft&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogs/millenial-guide-to-finance-3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On that same note, a great and cheap way to flex your actual trading abilities is to open up an account with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robinhood.com/&quot;&gt;Robinhood&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a quick, easy, nimble, and millenial-centric app. It cuts out transaction fees, has a streamlined UI, and is highly intuitive. This app would be a great place to start with a few hundred dollars just to test out what it feels like to buy and sell stock or mutual funds. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;b&gt;My 4 Simple Rules for Sound Financial Implementation&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This always seems like the next step after you’ve taken the time to read and learn about financial investing. I am going to say beforehand that the following simple rules should be taken with a grain of salt! There is no “best” way to invest or save, but there are certain things that can really help you get started on the right foot. Here we go:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;1. Consolidate you cash and streamline your liquidity.&lt;/b&gt; What this means is to get your money together from all of the accounts you have and develop a game-plan of how you hope to invest. Streamlining your liquidity means getting your processes down so that you can convert assets into cash easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2. Develop a strategy and STRUCTURE.&lt;/b&gt; Every sound financial plan has structure. My suggestion is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;25%-35%&lt;/b&gt; of your income and assets in bank checking and savings accounts for daily use, a rainy day, emergencies, vacations and fun.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;50-60%&lt;/b&gt; of your income and assets across your retirement accounts - 401K, 403, IRA, ROTH, SEP, whatever you choose is fine! Just know your accounts and why you have them as you start depositing.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;25-35%&lt;/b&gt; of your income and assets into your growth fund. You can view this as the money you hope to grow as a function of your risk profile. If you’re super risky, maybe this should be lower, or vice-versa. Again this is a personal choice, and there is no right or wrong answer. Make sure you draw the line somewhere. One way people lose lots of money is by not drawing a hard line on how much money they choose to risk in their portfolio. Make the plan, draw the line, and don’t deviate from it until you revisit your strategy for investing.	&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;3. Read all the time.&lt;/b&gt; Learn about finance, talk to your parents and friends about finance, and treat your financial understanding as part of your personal development. The sooner you realize this is part of your overall growth, the better. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;4. Re-evaluate your strategy.&lt;/b&gt; It’s really as simple as it sounds. Every 6 months, year or 2 years come back to your accounts. Consolidate your assets. Keep winners, sell losers, take profits and loses and rethink about how you are investing your money. This requires committment, diligence, and structure, but it’s the best way to make sure you don’t let your portfolio slide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;b&gt;More Food for Thought&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is always room for growth and additional learning. Maybe you’re already there (awesome!), but if not, just keep up reading and asking questions. You’ll learn by reading, reflecting and doing. When the time is right, take a look at some of these additional investment concepts that I think are important for all beginners:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Risk &amp;amp; Diversification are inversely related; i.e. to reduce risk you need to DIVERSIFY! How? Different securities; different markets.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Random Walk [ Market Makers v.s. Long Term Impact ]&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mutual Fund Returns vs Market Returns Historically&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Optimal Portfolio&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Currency Markets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is Arbitrage [ Free Lunch ]&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;20 Year Cycles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rollover Accounts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The concept of “riding the waves”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhay.com/finance/2015/01/18/A-Millenial-Guide-to-Finance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhay.com/finance/2015/01/18/A-Millenial-Guide-to-Finance.html</guid>
        
        <category>Investing</category>
        
        <category>Strategy</category>
        
        <category>Life-tools</category>
        
        <category>Personal development</category>
        
        <category>Banking</category>
        
        <category>Stocks</category>
        
        <category>Retirement Planning</category>
        
        <category>Good Reads</category>
        
        
        <category>finance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Entrepreneurs, Becoming Entrepreneurial, and Resources to Get You Started</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;b&gt;I am not an entrepreneur.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; 
	
I think the word, at one point in the past, had a unique and meaningful place in the language of US business jargon. But now it&#39;s become too out of touch with what it was intended to represent.
	

&lt;b&gt;Entrepreneurs were those contrarian individuals with grit, determination, clever ideas, and a wacky sense of world paradigms that allowed them to create new, interesting, and risky initiatives that drove measurable change.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bhorowitz.com/&quot;&gt;Ben Horowitz&lt;/a&gt; does a good job of defining the scope of a real entrepeneur. Read “&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2014/03/03/the-hard-thing-about-hard-things-ben-horowitzs-honest-and-real-take-on-entrepreneurship/&quot;&gt;The Hard Thing About Hard Things&lt;/a&gt;” to understand his perspective. I agree that if you haven’t woken up in the night with a cold sweat worrying about the fudiciary responsibility owed to your &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.usc.edu/presidentemeritus/contrarians-guide-to-leadership/&quot;&gt;lieutenants&lt;/a&gt; then you probably can’t claim ownership of the word. This is why I am not an entrepreneur – although, one day with a bit of luck and boatload of hard work, I hope to be distinguished enough to reach that pinnacle of impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not to say there still aren’t a lot of awesome entrepreneurs out there, but the world of technology and computing has led every smart 20+ year old with a knack for app development, or every business major with a creative idea to claim the title and set off on a destruction course. Are you shocked? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2014/03/16/magazine/silicon-valleys-youth-problem.html&quot;&gt;You shouldn’t be&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.entrepreneursforachange.com/10-stupid-business-ideas-that-made-millions/&quot;&gt;Having a cool idea&lt;/a&gt; doesn’t make you an entrepreneur. Failing doesn’t &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2014/11/09/business/wearing-your-failures-on-your-sleeve.html&quot;&gt;always&lt;/a&gt; make you an entrepreneur – but I agree failure is a stepping-stone to success, happiness, and growth! Raising money from hungry VCs also doesn’t make you an entrepreneur. &lt;b&gt;But there are plenty of things in the world that make you entrpreneurial.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What most people don’t understand or realize is that the qualities that make entrepreneurs great should be separated from the word that has now become vastly over-used. This is one of the great lessons I took away from &lt;a href=&quot;https://profiles.stanford.edu/thomas-byers&quot;&gt;Tom Byers&lt;/a&gt; and his legendary course on “&lt;a href=&quot;http://stvp.stanford.edu/about/&quot;&gt;Entrepreneurial Finance &amp;amp; Management&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what does it mean to be entrepreneurial? I am not in a position of supreme authority to shed much light, but I do have an opinion that I believe in: true entrepreneurship and genuine, authentic, classical leadership are inherently tied together. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Entrepreneurs, and great leaders, know what matters most. They understand people, demonstrate empathy, exude charisma, encourage feedback &amp;amp; optimism, and are devoted to both their own self-development and the development of others.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They reflect, improve, fail, and repeat the process in an effort to become better people – which in turns allows them to better lead those they serve,… and, surprisingly enough, lead better companies. And that’s a key distinction that can’t be forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good leaders recognize that they are acting as servants and stewards to others. Similarly, good entrepreneurs – real entrepreneurs – are “in it” for the impact. This isn’t always the case, but it should be; among &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/bruceupbin/2012/09/18/talking-philanthropy-with-marc-benioff/&quot;&gt;the entrepreneurs I admire the most&lt;/a&gt;, it most certainly is true. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond the soft contours of entrepreneurship that I have described, there is also a technical skillset that begets those who practice entrepreneurship. In my mind, this isn’t just software development or computer science. You don’t have to be a coder or programmer, but analytical prowess and a fascination with math, science, finance, businessn, strategy, and product development are certainly some popular pillars. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re like me, you’re probably thinking, “this is great and all, but so what?” Not everyone has time to dedicate themselves to the study of these diverse fields, and even if you did, just starting can be complicated and stressful. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “so what” is that anyone – you, me, your younger sister, your older manager, she, he, or them – &lt;b&gt;anyone&lt;/b&gt; can become more entrepreneurial, can practice entrepreneurship and therein become a better leader and person. Like most things in life, all it takes is committing to learning and growing. Boom: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2008/07/06/business/06unbox.html&quot;&gt;Growth Mindset 101&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you have it. From my point of view, that’s really the power of entrepreneurship. And to get you started, I’ve assembled a list of my favorite reads on just this. Many kudos to the mentors &amp;amp; advisors who have helped me with these wonderful resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Resources to Get Started: Entrepreneurship Good Reads&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list(s) below capture some of the best thoughts from awesome leaders, entrepreneurs, VCs, creators, developers, educators, and others. This doesn’t capture even a fraction of the great content out there, so keep scouring the world and send me recommendations! Look at this as a starting point – a launchpad to help you become more entrepreneurial. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt; Blogs: &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bhorowitz.com/&quot;&gt;http://bhorowitz.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://andreessenhorowitz.com&quot;&gt;http://andreessenhorowitz.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://steveblank.com/&quot;&gt;http://steveblank.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.venturehacks.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.venturehacks.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.avc.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.avc.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bothsidesofthetable.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.bothsidesofthetable.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://startuplessonslearned.blogspot.com&quot;&gt;http://startuplessonslearned.blogspot.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://redeye.firstround.com/&quot;&gt;http://redeye.firstround.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forentrepreneurs.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.forentrepreneurs.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;ttp://www.cbinsights.com/research­reports/Silicon­Valley­Venture­Capital­Almanac.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.cbinsights.com/research­reports/Silicon­Valley­Venture­Capital­Almanac.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onstartups.com/&quot;&gt;http://onstartups.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.paulgraham.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.askthevc.com&quot;&gt;http://www.askthevc.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.feld.com&quot;&gt;http://www.feld.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trevorloy.com&quot;&gt;http://www.trevorloy.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Also, generally &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fastcompany.com/&quot;&gt;FastCompany&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/&quot;&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt; can be INCREDIBLE places to learn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt; Books &amp;amp; Articles:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2014/03/03/the-hard-thing-about-hard-things-ben-horowitzs-honest-and-real-take-on-entrepreneurship/&quot;&gt;The Hard Thing About Hard things&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;How Will You Measure Your Life?&lt;/a&gt;” by Clayton Christensen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://about.usc.edu/presidentemeritus/contrarians-guide-to-leadership/&quot;&gt;Contrarian’s Guide to Leadership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fastcompany.com/1786824/leadership-hall-fame-warren-bennis-author-becoming-leader&quot;&gt;On Becoming a Leader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/keldjensen/2013/02/05/why-negotiators-still-arent-getting-to-yes/&quot;&gt;Getting to Yes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Difficult-Conversations-Discuss-What-Matters/dp/0143118447&quot;&gt;Difficult Conversations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/86d97610-00ab-11df-ae8d-00144feabdc0.html#axzz3OxWR4tBz&quot;&gt;‘Airline pilot’ protocols in finance&lt;/a&gt;” by Atul Gawande&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.claytonchristensen.com/books/the-innovators-dilemma/&quot;&gt;The Innovator’s Dilemma&lt;/a&gt;” by Clayton Christensen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“An Introduction to Stocks and Options for the Tech Entrepreneur or Employee” by David Weekly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2014/10/marc-andreessen-in-conversation.html&quot;&gt;On Optimism&lt;/a&gt; by Marc Andreessen… there are so many other great reads on Optimism though! Don’t let this value escape you!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fastcompany.com/3033993/hit-the-ground-running/the-intangible-career-trait-that-you-need-to-succeed&quot;&gt;Executive Presence&lt;/a&gt; as seen on FC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Crossing the Chasm” by G. Moore&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“The Founder’s Dilemma” by Naom Wasserman&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forentrepreneurs.com/saas-metrics-2/&quot;&gt;SaaS Metrics 2.0 ­ A Guide to Measuring and Improving What Matters&lt;/a&gt;”” by David Skok&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;The Entrepreneurs Guide to Business Law&lt;/a&gt; by Bagley and Dauchy. This was actually a great recommendation from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flywheelventures.com/index.php/website/flywheel_team/&quot;&gt;Trevor Loy&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a leading reference book for legal issues surrounding entrepreneurship and is one of those books that gives you essential jargon and “skills-based” knowledge. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“How to Write a Great Business Plan” by William Sahlman&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;The Neatest Little Guide to Stock Market Investing&lt;/a&gt;”” by Jason Kelly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;http://abovethecrowd.com/2009/08/24/what-is-really-happening-to-the-venture-capital-industry/&quot;&gt;What is Really Happening to the Venture Capital Industry&lt;/a&gt;” by Bill Gurley of Benchmark Capital&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Business Plan’s That Work” from Zacharakis, Spinelli and Timmons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;http://ospflor63.stanford.edu/upload/handouts/Secret_Sauce_-_Seelig.pdf&quot;&gt;The Secret Sauce of Silicon Valley” by Tina Seelig in “What I Wish I Knew When I Was 20&lt;/a&gt;“
“&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sramanamitra.com/2014/01/27/who-are-the-top-vcs-in-silicon-valley-today/&quot;&gt;Who Are The Top VCs in Silicon Valley Today?&lt;/a&gt;””&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/02/welcome-to-the-unicorn-club/&quot;&gt;Welcome To The Unicorn Club: Learning From Billion­-Dollar Startups&lt;/a&gt;” from Aileen Lee.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Why the Lean Start­Up Changes Everything” by Steve Blank&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Generally, anything about &lt;a href=&quot;http://qz.com/317918/holacracy-at-zappos-its-either-the-future-of-management-or-a-social-experiment-gone-awry/&quot;&gt;Holacracy&lt;/a&gt; (…or Holo-crazy as I’ve sometimes experienced it!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in case you’re a glutton for punishment, here’s some other informative and awesome reads that will open up your mind to better leadership…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“The Prince” Niccolo Machiavelli&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“The Secrets of Storytelling” by Jeremy Hsu&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Super People” by James Atlas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Cowboys and Pit Crews” by Atul Gawande&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Earn More Respect” by Warren Bennis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhay.com/entrepreneurship/2015/01/14/Entrepreneurs-Becoming-Entrepreneurial-Resources-to-Get-You-Started%20copy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhay.com/entrepreneurship/2015/01/14/Entrepreneurs-Becoming-Entrepreneurial-Resources-to-Get-You-Started%20copy.html</guid>
        
        <category>Self Development</category>
        
        <category>Strategy</category>
        
        <category>Leadership</category>
        
        <category>Good Reads</category>
        
        
        <category>entrepreneurship</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Opening Up Open Graph</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As I’ve dug deeper into how content is displayed across the web, I’ve found that it’s not always as rosy as I’d like. A big problem is that I am a total &lt;code&gt;n00b&lt;/code&gt; and don’t always get my code just right when writing up my thoughts. In turn this means my pages don’t always display correctly across different applicaitons like Facebook or Linked-In. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See how lame this looks? Nobody is going to read this without a picture and some awesome OG tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/open-graph-ex-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After doing some research, I’ve found there are amazing &lt;code&gt;meta&lt;/code&gt; tags out there that fall under &lt;a href=&quot;http://ogp.me/&quot;&gt;OpenGraph&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept and application is simple. Whenever you list your site on the internet, web crawlers look for &lt;code&gt;meta&lt;/code&gt; tags to compile information about your site and map it within their database. The more &lt;code&gt;meta&lt;/code&gt; information you have the better, as it makes it easier for your website to be properly linked and mapped in a web-search. Beyond this, Facebook, Twitter, and other social media sites use OpenGraph tags in order to generate previews for articles and webpages among many other things. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;implementation&quot;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic code structure for open graph meta tags is simple:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;meta property=&quot;&quot; content=&quot;&quot; /&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are different properties as well. Here are a few to get you started:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;property=&quot;og:title&quot;
property=&quot;og:image&quot; 
property=&quot;og:site&quot;
property=&quot;og:description&quot;
property=&quot;og:type&quot;
property=&quot;og:url&quot;
property=&quot;article:author
property=&quot;article:section&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there you just have to enter the &lt;code&gt;&quot;content&quot;&lt;/code&gt; portion of the code. If you’re doing it with static pages then this is just &lt;code&gt;text&lt;/code&gt;, otherwise you should generate it dynamically. For my own purposes, I used &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.shopify.com/themes/liquid-documentation/basics&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;liquid tags&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and plugged into the power of &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; to generate my tags automatically for every static page I work up. Here’s a code snippet from my website of what this would actually look like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/open-graph-ex-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and it’s VERY important to remember to call the &lt;code&gt;og&lt;/code&gt; tag in the beginning of the &lt;code&gt;html&lt;/code&gt;. Just throw this in your &lt;code&gt;head&lt;/code&gt; section somewhere:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;html prefix=&quot;og: http://ogp.me/ns#&quot;/&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, this doesn’t even scratch the surface of all the cool things that OpenGraph can deliver. Explore it on your own and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.austinhay.com/contact&quot;&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt; what you find. Here are some fun resources that you might check out with more time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gavick.com/blog/controlling-facebook-link-previews-and-getting-to-know-open-graph&quot;&gt;Getting to Know Open Graph&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iacquire.com/blog/18-meta-tags-every-webpage-should-have-in-2013&quot;&gt;Essential Meta Tags from 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to &lt;a href=&quot;http://davidensinger.com/2013/04/adding-open-graph-tags-to-jekyll/&quot;&gt;implement&lt;/a&gt; in Jekyll, like I did.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhay.com/coding/2015/01/08/Opening-Up-Open-Graph.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhay.com/coding/2015/01/08/Opening-Up-Open-Graph.html</guid>
        
        <category>Web Development</category>
        
        <category>Software</category>
        
        <category>Blogging Essentials</category>
        
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
