<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Austin A. Hay</title>
    <description> is a millenial blogger, engineer &amp; operater focused on strategy, leadership, self-developement, entrepreneurship, and rookie programming. Don&#39;t be a stranger - drop me an email to connect. Contents and code &amp;copy; 2015</description>
    <link>http://austinhay.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://austinhay.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 20:33:38 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 20:33:38 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sell or Be Sold: Mobile World Congress 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When we first touched down in Barcelona two weeks ago it was hard to believe I was really there. Just three days before I got a late night call from one of our co-founders with a simple question: &lt;b&gt;Want to go to Spain?&lt;/b&gt; At first I thought she was joking - or maybe referring to a far off conference in the summer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageright-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mobileworldcongress.com/&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/mwc-2015/sell-or-be-sold-1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 96%; padding: 1%;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;font-style: italic; padding-top: 4%;&quot;&gt;
    With less than 48 hours to spare, we were headed to Barcelona to represent Branch at Mobile World Congress 2015. Talk about a wild ride...
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, she was talking about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mobileworldcongress.com/&quot;&gt;Mobile World Congress 2015&lt;/a&gt; (MWC), arguably the most relevant and compelling gathering of mobile ecosystem leaders from across the globe. It happens every year - more than 90,000 people congregate in Barcelona at the Grand Fira conference center for four days to meet business partners, make new strategic relationships, survey mobile competition, unveil new products, and showcase the power of mobile as a defining part of innovation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My journey to MWC began moments after I hung up the phone that fateful Thursday night. It was time to prepare. For most companies, MCW takes serveral months of preperation, but not at &lt;a href=&quot;https://branch.io&quot;&gt;Branch&lt;/a&gt;. After our recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2015/02/26/branch-metrics-raises-15-million-for-its-smarter-mobile-deep-linking-technology/&quot;&gt;Series A&lt;/a&gt; we saw a great opportunity to build relationships, evangelize Branch, make a notable presence, and to learn about the mobile ecosystem. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who said you couldn’t pull off an incredibly successful MWC trip in three days? 4 days, 30 miles walking, 100’s of partner meetings, 20 cafe con leches, dozens of cocktail hours, and 18 hour crunches later, this is my story: &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grantcardone.com/sell-or-be-sold/&quot;&gt;Sell or Be Sold&lt;/a&gt;: Conquering &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mobileworldcongress.com/&quot;&gt;MWC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-adventure-beginswith-an-app&quot;&gt;The Adventure Begins…with an App&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most difficult parts of building relationships is the time it takes to manually enter contact information and to properly follow up. Business cards are great but leave you with no lasting memory of the person and what they have to offer. Most people ask for specific requests - they want the link to that PDF you were talking about, or they want to be engaged with your technology in a specific way. The thing that doesn’t change, however, is remembering to log their details, connect, and follow up. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageleft-1&quot; style=&quot;width:30%;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://branch.io&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/mwc-2015/sell-or-be-sold-2.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 96%; padding: 1%;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;font-style: italic; padding-top: 4%;&quot;&gt;
    Why spend hours logging business cards when we could connect with people right away?
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this insight in mind, I started wondering if there were any apps that did this specific task with high resolution. &lt;b&gt;What business productivity tools would allow me to easily connect with those I met at MWC and place them straight into my CRM so that I could easily manage my relationship with them moving forward?&lt;/b&gt; Even more, was there a way that I could streamline when and how I followed up with these individuals?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the heart of this issue was the fact that it takes a lot of time to follow up between manually entering business card information and typing out hundreds of personalized emails. In my experience, by the time I get around to drafting follow up emails, I’ve already forgotten the context of how I met the person, the nuances of our relationship, and if I needed to include any important details. There had to be an easier way to shoot the person an email and connect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our “eureka” moment about this business problem hit &lt;a href=&quot;http://derrrick.com/&quot;&gt;Derrick Staten&lt;/a&gt; and I as we sat on the runway at SFO on our way to Spain. Derrick is a gifted iOS developer with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/ellenhuet/2014/09/15/the-league-dating-app-for-the-elite/&quot;&gt;experience&lt;/a&gt; building awesome apps, so his solution came naturally… why don’t we build an iOS app specifically for us to help solve this problem?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of our grueling 12-hour flight to Paris we worked together to build an incredible app that solved all of these problems and tied in to our Branch backend. We also dropped Branch links into our app so that when we connected with people we met at MWC we could better understand how our tech might better serve them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app, in its simplest form, takes the mundane - manually writing an email days after you meet somebody - and turns it into a fun and instananeous process. When we landed later in Barcelona, we tested our prototype and were amazed at the business need this simple app provided. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageright-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/mwc-2015/sell-or-be-sold-3.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 96%; padding: 1%;&quot; /&gt;

  &lt;p style=&quot;font-style: italic; padding-top: 4%;&quot;&gt;
  It&#39;s hard to believe that we crunched out an entire application on the airplane. By the time we touched down in Paris we were ready to deploy not only our app, but ourselves, at MWC!
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It begs the question: should more app developers hit the skies for their next big idea?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;el-cafe-la-fuma-y-las-ramblas&quot;&gt;El Cafe, La Fuma, y Las Ramblas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building an app over the Atlantic was not enough to satiate our thirst for adventure as we took to the streets in Barcelona. First, we found our home for the week in the Gothic district with Luisa, our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/users/show/3392163&quot;&gt;Airbnb host&lt;/a&gt; and one of the most welcoming Spaniards I’ve ever met. Then it was time to explore. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was in high school I had lived in Santander and experienced Spain in a way that few 16 year old’s ever do. The things I loved about Barcelona still enamored me as we walked the streets - tortilla de Espana, churros con chocolate, crowded alleyways, signs of la siesta, las ramblas, families out and about at 11 in the evening, and the many plazas with outdoor places to sit, relax, take in the lights and have a glass of wine. Spain is a beautiful country and Barcelona brought back feelings of home I hadn’t felt since living along the northern coast. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;4&quot; style=&quot;float:left; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 2%; max-width:329px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/p/zskUbVhJ1u/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Barcelona nights. So stoked to be repping @branchmetrics at Mobile World Congress! #mwc2015 #barcelona #spain #mobilegrowth #deeplinking #quelinda #noche&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Austin Hay (@austinahay) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2015-03-01T19:12:04+00:00&quot;&gt;Mar 1, 2015 at 11:12am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;grinding-out-the-days&quot;&gt;Grinding out the Days&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These feelings were quickly swapped for ones of a more intense flavor as we dove into the grind that is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mobileworldcongress.com/&quot;&gt;MWC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who aren’t familiar with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mobileworldcongress.com/&quot;&gt;Mobile World Congress&lt;/a&gt;, it’s a four-day sprint where attendees and partners in the mobile hardware, software, applications and everything in between, gather to talk business, showcase their products, and meet as many people as possible. It’s incredibly demanding, both physcially and mentally, but it provides a deep dive into the mobile landscape that no other single event really can. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This aspect of our adventure started at 6 AM Monday morning as we grabbed a quick coffee and started the multi-mile walk and subway travel to the Grand Fira, a goliath conference complex with over eight independent conference buildings, each the size of football stadium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The days were grueling. Every minute was spent taking in the mobile landscape, searching for interesting partnerships, and talking to everyone and anyone. I’m a fundamental believer in people so every conversation took time. Cultivating relationships isn’t easy… it takes time, attention to detail, and the willingness to give people your full self for a period of time. It isn’t enough to say “hello” and talk business. If you want to hook people and keep them engaged you have to look at the conversation as a two way road - one that usually begins with deep listening and learning. This was the process for my partner and I, as we spent the first part of every new conversation asking questions, trying to understand the person and company at hand, and then, only after listening intently for a few minutes, trying to find a way that &lt;a href=&quot;https://branch.io/links&quot;&gt;Branch&lt;/a&gt; might fit with their business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageright&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bhorowitz.com/the_struggle&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/mwc-2015/sell-or-be-sold-4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;font-style: italic; padding-top: 4%;&quot;&gt;
  This is just a small part of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bhorowitz.com/the_struggle&quot;&gt;Startup Struggle&lt;/a&gt; that Ben Horowitz outlines. A packed 4 day schedule calls for coffee and persistence.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That might be one of the most obvious lessons in the business – &lt;b&gt;selling isn’t about convincing people, it’s about listening.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These conversations made up the bulk of our trip. When we weren’t finding new people to meet we were back at our Airbnb resting or preparing for the next day. Unfortunately, we didn’t find enough time to explore all that Barcelona has to offer in terms of culture - but we’ll be back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;killer-tips-on-how-to-win-mwc&quot;&gt;Killer Tips on How to Win MWC&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part of MWC 2015 was the firsthand experience of joining the conference last minute. By now, you’re probably wondering 1.) if we were successful in our endeavors, and 2.) what we took away from the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the conversations throughout the week we attended MWC taught us a lot about sales, Branch, mobile, technology and ourselves. The value of listening wasn’t the only lesson. Here’s a list of the top takeaways that are easy to consider when planning your MWC visit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Plan Ahead&lt;/b&gt;: It goes without saying, but planning in three days is incredibly complicated and made things stressful. Next year if we decide to go to MWC we will definitely plan at least 1 - 2 months ahead of schedule.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageright-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/mwc-2015/sell-or-be-sold-5.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;font-style: italic; padding-top: 4%;&quot;&gt;
  Planning ahead is more than just knowing that you&#39;re going to MWC - you should map out exactly where you plan to spend your days at MWC. We spent most of our time at App World. Figure out where you&#39;ll find the most value and double down in targetting your business relations.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hotel&lt;/b&gt;: Location and accommodations both matter. This year we stayed in an Airbnb in the Gothic District near Career d’Boquer (Princessa and Montcada) — this was a central location and was actually perfect. We highly recommend something in this neighborhood for anwyone looking to double down on both the Fira events and the post-day cocktail hours and parties held in the heart of Barcelona. While Airbnb was perfect for our last minute stay, it also had many downsides: 1) not very clean, 2) bad perception for guests or outside parties - couldn’t have meetings there, which was huge bummer, 3) illicit activities that made us uncomfortable (hahaha), and 4) exact residence felt somewhat unsafe. Generally, the Airbnb made our stay much more complicated and less efficient than it could have been. Staying in a hotel would remove this friction and allow people to focus more on what they are there for: MWC. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Number of Attendees&lt;/b&gt;: Generally speaking, it would have been nice to have 4-6 people in total. At least two more would have made it much easier to:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;1) Scour the floor for good possible leads.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;2) Set up pre-planned productive meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Booths are expensive and not really necessary: We found that big booths in the App World section (Hall 8) were actually very expensive (&amp;gt; $50,000 each) and tied down members to a specific location. We believe that Branch could be more effective if you’re not tied down to a booth and can go from convo to convo. Alternatively, if we do a booth we still need to make sure we have scouts on the floor meeting new leads. A small booth could easily be managed by two people.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageleft-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://branch.io&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/mwc-2015/sell-or-be-sold-6.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;font-style: italic; padding-top: 4%;&quot;&gt;
  Sometimes, there&#39;s just no replacement for pounding pavement. Every team going to MWC should have a plan A, a plan B, and even a plan C, but at the end of the day, what&#39;s going to help the most is by putting boots on the ground and executing. You have to be prepared to talk to as many partners as you can. It can be exhausting, but it&#39;s the way to win.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Set Meetings&lt;/b&gt;: Your team should do everything possible to block off time on the calendar with the most important partners and send your best people to those meetings. Even though we did a good job explaining our tech, it would have been even better if we had sent people who were able to make executive level decisions about how we might work together. Since the conference contains many larger players, and far fewer app developers, for companies looking to engage in mobile software and app development, the focus of this conference should be more geared towards Business Development and Strategic Relations. Look to develop a specific and tailored objective, agenda, message, and knowledge of how you would work with the intended partner (replacing or working with specific technologies). The more specific, the better!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Volume Matters&lt;/b&gt;: There is no way to know in advance how good the quality of a potential lead might be. The only way to be successful is to hit as many people as possible! We found that it was most effective to focus our attention together, as a team, in the beginning, and “divide and conquer” once the primary list of potential partners had been depleted. This strategy may work well or not well depending on your goals and the resources you have available. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, in the future, I think it’s best to consider having a team that constantly hits the floor to do just this: meet anyone and everyone. Meanwhile, another team can focus more of their attention on specialized meetings and strategic prospecting. This feeds back into why a team of four would be very important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageright-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/mwc-2015/sell-or-be-sold-7.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;font-style: italic; padding-top: 4%;&quot;&gt;
  A good place to practice is at the 4YFN -- there are tons of great startups that give you the opportunity to test different prop values, listen, and make great friends in the app ecosystem!
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Know Your Competition&lt;/b&gt;: It’s not just enough to know who they are, but also what they are doing and how you will respond to them. The reality is that most competitors use Mobile World Congress to talk to one another and actually scout the competitive landscape. Make sure you know who your “primary competitors” are before and prepare a list of questions you might get asked. Beyond this, make sure your boots on the ground are prepared! Make a list of the the things your company does not want to discuss — especially proprietary technology, future visions, or strategic partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Develop Consistent Messaging&lt;/b&gt;: At Branch, we explain our technology and company in many flavors (perhaps too many), but the ultimate story we distribute is consistent. This is incredibly important for your employees and for your business partners. Consistent messaging makes it clear who you are, what you do, and how you might serve them. It also makes it easy for your employees to remember how to explain your culture, brand, technology, and future.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Develop Training Docs &amp;amp; PRACTICE&lt;/b&gt;: This should go without saying. Develop killer training docs to prepare all those who are attending under you company umbrella. Don’t stop with the “travelling basics,” dive deeper into why your company is attending, who you are looking to meet, what type of strategic partnerships you hope to gain, and your pitching plan. The more you do to formalize your thoughts beforehand, the less you leave to error. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageright-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://branch.io&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/mwc-2015/sell-or-be-sold-8.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;font-style: italic; padding-top: 4%;&quot;&gt;
    There will be many different social events to attend at MWC. Don&#39;t be distracted by the noise! Find events where you know at least 1 or 2 partners and they are willing to introduce you to leads that fit your goals.  
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;T-Shirt Handouts&lt;/b&gt;: T-shirts and other swag are essential for startups to help spread their brand and delight potential future customres. However, we recommend keeping the swag handouts to a minimum at MWC. First off, there are over 90,000 people in attendance. There is simply no way you can cover all your bases. You will run out of whatever materials you bring, so choose wisely. More importantly, MWC is a bit more formal than Hackathons or other events. It was very difficult to hand out T-shirts and give away free swag (aka build good relations and spread our brand) when you are also operating out on the fly - and usually out of bags and backpacks. Keep swag - if any -  for a dedicated booth or meetup.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Meetups Should be Official&lt;/b&gt;: Not only should meetups, or compant events, be planned well in advance, but they should be conducted through official channels: i.e. the 4YFN, MWC, or other event sponsors, or conducted at a restaurant so it has a dedicated location. If at a restaurant, make sure to specify that you’ll have a presence and work with the owners/operators to reserve space and put up signage. We think flyers alone, without a presence and dedicated plan, don’t work. This all may sound obvious, but for young companies working on the fly, it might seem tempting to plan an ad hoc happy hour. The reality is that at MWC people block their calendars well in advance. Stay away from on the fly meetings - plan ahead!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Parties with Personal Invites&lt;/b&gt;: There are many parties during MWC to attend and we found the most effective ones were those where we knew at least 1+ of the planners or attendees who was willing to introduce us to other attendees. A good example was at the Picasso Museum tour our first night where a good friend from Relay Ventures introduced us to two of his friends. From there we were able to be introduced to many more. Comparatively, at other parties we attended without a friend or sponsor contact, we found it difficult to meet and qualify opportunities in the same way. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;On-The-Ground Assistance&lt;/b&gt;: For us, our on the ground support was &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lidahasbrouck&quot;&gt;Lida&lt;/a&gt;, an awesome Branch employee back at home, who pulled in the clutch when things got crazy in Barcelona. Everyone going to MWC needs their Lida. It’s just too crazy of an event not to have a dedicated staff member to support those closing deals at the Gran Fira. 
. This may sound ridiculous, but between travel, 10 mile walks, 18 hour days, it just helps to have someone there.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageleft-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/branchmetrics/past-present-future-of-branch-metrics&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/mwc-2015/sell-or-be-sold-10.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;font-style: italic; padding-top: 4%;&quot;&gt;
  It&#39;s simple. And it&#39;s what our Founders like to &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/branchmetrics/past-present-future-of-branch-metrics&quot;&gt;live by&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;measuring-success&quot;&gt;Measuring Success&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we finally sank into our seats Thursday morning at 6 AM on an outbound flight to San Francisco, it felt like an eternity had passed by. Derrick and I collapsed, sleeping half the flight. It all seemed like a dream…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In less than 72 hours we had cultivated over 100 business relationships, made an internal business app, hosted a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.branch.io/meetups&quot;&gt;meetup&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://venturebeat.com/2015/03/05/branch-metrics-comes-up-with-gold-at-mobile-world-congress-startup-showdown/&quot;&gt;won a startup pitch&lt;/a&gt;, and attended over a dozen after-hours parties. We operated on what felt like 10 total hours of sleep, drank five coffees a day, logged all our learnings and left feeling like we had done everything possible to make the most of our time in Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is probably the true metric of success: feeling like you’ve driven as hard as you can and have nothing else to give. Winning at MWC means leaving it all on the Fira floor. Times like this remind me of an important mantra we live by here at Branch…&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhay.com/branch/2015/03/06/Sell-or-Be-Sold-MWC-2015.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhay.com/branch/2015/03/06/Sell-or-Be-Sold-MWC-2015.html</guid>
        
        <category>Mobile</category>
        
        <category>Native</category>
        
        <category>MobileWorldCongress</category>
        
        <category>MWC</category>
        
        <category>MWC-2015</category>
        
        <category>Barcelona</category>
        
        <category>Deeplinking</category>
        
        <category>Software</category>
        
        <category>Spain</category>
        
        <category>Personal Development</category>
        
        
        <category>branch</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Collaborative Sales</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone has felt quota anxiety - that feeling you get when your sales lead puts an often arbitrary number on the &lt;u&gt;quantity&lt;/u&gt; of interactions you need to have  with others &lt;u&gt;per unit of time&lt;/u&gt;. Sometimes it’s cold outbounds per quarter, sometimes it’s calls per week. No matter what unit of measurement you look at, these quotas are inherently created to drive competition and maximize employee performance. But does it really work? Or does it cause more toxicity to your sales team than it does productivity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;imageright&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogs/collaborative-sales-1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-new-type-of-selling&quot;&gt;A New Type of Selling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone who’s seen Glengarry Glen Ross knows Alec Baldwin’s infamous Art of Selling scene in which he breaks down sales into a contest - 3rd prize is that you’re fired. Baldwin goes on to make some seemingly ridiculous quotes: “Leads are weak? You’re weak.” Sprinkled in are notes of sexism and the punch-line… Always be closing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;imageleft&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;auto&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3oQZsuJyy-U&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sales teams often walk far too close to this comical distopia. It may seem innocuous, but strip away all the dramatic lines, the yelling, the ridiculous analogies, and you’re still left with the dangerous undertones created by hyper-competitive sales. Sales competition not only leads to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tlnt.com/2012/01/10/10-destructive-behaviors-that-can-bring-down-a-team%E2%80%99s-success/&quot;&gt;destructive behaviors&lt;/a&gt; that can tear the sales org apart, but it’s now being questioned as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://enterprise-gamification.com/index.php?option=com_content&amp;amp;view=article&amp;amp;id=197:9-reasons-why-competition-is-bad-for-sales&amp;amp;catid=10&amp;amp;Itemid=16&amp;amp;lang=en&quot;&gt;best practice&lt;/a&gt; in driving effective sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not to say that some forms of competition aren’t healthy. Competitive sales has been around forever, but there is room for newer, more collaborative sales models that focus on productivity and employee well-being rather than arbitrary bottom lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, for high-tech companies that work very closely with developers in growing their organization through the installation of SDKs or other drop in code, collaborative sales is the key to success. Github speaks to this in a recent podcast:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/194421673&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;inverse=false&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_user=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-perception-the-problem-with-sales-competition&quot;&gt;My Perception: The Problem With Sales Competition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of other people have noted the problems with competitive sales, but in my experience, there are a few things that are worth highlighting. All of these are my own opinions and thoughts. Others might disagree or have found a competitive sales team mindset that works! That’s okay. What’s more important is being aware of how others function and adapating your sales team to be as productive as possible. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Competition incentivizes individual accomplishment and success over company goals.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Competition means splitting up value based on quantity &amp;amp; individual, which is wrong! Everyone should feel compelled to jump in and help sell and evangelize your product!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Without collaboration on the sales team, members may try to keep “secrets” to selling that help them pull greater numbers than other team members. This is immensely toxic and discourages feedback and improvement both at the process and individual level.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Competition makes it hard to learn: everyone brings a certain set of strengths and weaknesses to sales. If we incentivize numbers, people will lose sight of their long-term ability to be awesome at evangelizing your company.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, you’re likely left wondering &lt;b&gt;is it possible to adapt to every single person’s needs?&lt;/b&gt; Unfortunately, the answer is no, probably not. But that isn’t to say that you can’t try to be more accomodating. The reality is that whatever set of sales rules you choose to integrate might rub off wrongly against particular personalities. However, don’t forget that only you have the power to adapt your team and make it more productive. &lt;b&gt;Don’t accept the sales status quo because it’s business as usual&lt;/b&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.branch.io/ideas-are-the-currency-of-growth/&quot;&gt;same advice&lt;/a&gt; that Morgan Brown vocalizes about growth applies applies to sales: &lt;b&gt;it is an iterative and idea-centric process&lt;/b&gt;. Try new things, test what works and what doesn’t, capture valuable metrics, get feedback, learn, improve, and double down when you’ve figured out the best way for your org to sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;collaborative-sales-explained&quot;&gt;Collaborative Sales Explained&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaborative sales concentrates on the team-centric nature of selling. Less focus is placed on gathering a numerical volume of leads, and more focus is placed on cultivating real business fits. &lt;b&gt;Whereas competitive sales is transactional, collaborative sales is relational.&lt;/b&gt; Collaborative sales cares about: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.) High quality business connections.
2.) Product &amp;amp; company evangelism.
3.) A change in mindset &amp;amp; jargon: relationship building vs selling.
4.) Knowledge sharing.
5.) Data-driven selling and team self-awareness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These core tenets of collaborative sales not only lead to a more productive sales team, but they can help reduce the anxiety that often goes hand-in-hand with hyper-competition. More imporantly, by focusing on collaboration and sharing you will create an environment where all sales team-members learn and improve, burn out less frequently (or at all), focus on the company’s success, put the the customer first, and, generally, sell more intelligently. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;collaborative-sales-in-action&quot;&gt;Collaborative Sales in Action&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talkin’ the talk is not enough with collaborative sales - you also need to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qIOFs2onNE0&quot;&gt;walk the walk&lt;/a&gt;. To help sales teams convert, I can point out how collabortive sales worked for my team at &lt;a href=&quot;https://branch.io&quot;&gt;Branch&lt;/a&gt; during Mobile World Congress 2015. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two-person sales team worked together the entire conference, generating over 100 leads with a &amp;gt; 25% lead reply rate over 3 days. Part of this was due to the nature of the conference, but, I believe, much of this was due to collaborative sales. &lt;b&gt;So what did collaborative sales in action look like for us?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developed an iOS application tool together as a team, that would streamline our sales cycle and allow us to count our total number of leads so we could calculate our total ROI. Amazing meeting of technical talent, sales need, product cycle, and just raw teamwork. It was a great bonding activity that added huge value to our trip and our follow up in the sales cycle. We did this on the plane to Barcelona in a few hours!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;imageleft&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogs/collaborative-sales-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Set expectations upfront that we would work together and not set daily quotas, but that we had a cumulative number we wanted to get &lt;b&gt;together&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Agreed to communicate and give each other feedback on our pitching abilities, how we presented ourselves in front of partners, how we spoke about technical aspects of our product, and how we followed up.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Worked the conference floor as a team in order to properly prospect the best partners in the area we identified as “most relevant.””&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Split up when necessary to give ourselves a break, experiment, move quickly, and improve our independent selling abilities. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Both of us switched off engaging with very potential important partners to build our experience. This allowed us to build our independent selling skills, and learn how to take subtle cues.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Over time, we became more comfortable listening, understanding one another’s statements, and contributing valuable information that made for a better presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-takeaways&quot;&gt;Final Takeaways&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many advocates for competitive sales - I’m not here to discredit these techniques. I am here to say, however, that new sales teams should consider exploring new techniques when establishing a culture at their sales organization. Quotas are good, but are short-sighted and don’t focus on the long-term prosperity of a sales orgs’ people or their ability to deliver results quarter after quarter. And in a world where people are the heart and soul of a company’s success, I think collaborative sales orgs can deliver incredible sales results while maintaining the best sales talent.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhay.com/sales/2015/03/06/Collaborative-Sales.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhay.com/sales/2015/03/06/Collaborative-Sales.html</guid>
        
        <category>Collaboration</category>
        
        <category>Lessons Learned</category>
        
        <category>Selling</category>
        
        <category>Branch Metrics</category>
        
        <category>Personal Development</category>
        
        
        <category>sales</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Podcasting Takeaways - Part 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I began working at &lt;a href=&quot;http://branch.io&quot;&gt;Branch Metrics&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve had the privilege of curating the content and strategy behind our Podcast outreach. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, I drew a lot of inspiration from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mvc&quot;&gt;Michael Copeland&lt;/a&gt; over at the A16Z podcast station. As I started doing more podcasts, I learned some important lessons on creating audio that is well-curated, compelling, thoughtful, interesting, exciting,  and fun. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;imageleft&quot; style=&quot;width:60%;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/users/138903540&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the future, as I learn, grow, and publish more podcasts, I will throw back all the lessons I’ve learned under the same series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tips-from-a-month-in-podcasting&quot;&gt;Tips from a Month in Podcasting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;1.) Voice is everything:&lt;/b&gt; It might seem cliche, but I couldn’t stress this point more. Your voice and the voices of othes are what make a podcast rock or die before it gets published. As I’ve progressed in the last month I’ve had to listen to my voice hundreds of times. This has caused me to reflect on how I sound, not only to myself but to others – do I talk loud, quiet, fast, slow, or strange? What are the words I use too often? How do I ask questions? A huge part of improving your podcast outreach is having an excellent interviewer. If you’re taking on this role then don’t be afraid to reflect, get feedback and make changes to the way you use your voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2.) Set the right expectations:&lt;/b&gt; A lot of speakers come into podcasts not knowing what to expect. Instead of hoping that they will get it right automatically, just be upfront in your expectations! Specifically, acknowledge how you want your podcast to flow, what flavor of questions you will ask, how you will ask those questions, what type of responses you think your audience will care about and anything else that you think will benefit them in knowing. This was some of the feedback I got early on from my first few podcasts and it has been a guiding principle ever since - don’t leave anything to chance. Be upfront, be honest, be genuine, and set your expectations early. Confirm them as often as you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;3.) Laughing can kill the flow:&lt;/b&gt; I like to smile and laugh a lot. Unfortunately, this doesn’t do well for my podcasts. In general, laughing can disrupt the flow of the speakers’ voices and can cause an uncomfortable interruption in the thought process of those listening. If something is funny, it’s okay to laugh on a podcast, but in general you should think about how hard you are laughing and if it really is necessary for the situation. If all else fails, take it down a notch and try chuckling instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;4.) Timing your questions perfectly:&lt;/b&gt; The goal of the interviewer is to guide the discussion, ask meaningful and related questions, and create a unified theme around the podcast. Much of this is done by asking questions at the right time. In general, I’ve found there are two important things to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;reasons-to-ask-questions&quot;&gt;Reasons to Ask Questions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Acknowlegment &amp;amp; Elaboration: You ask a question to confirm you understand what the speaker is saying and to inquire for deeper elaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Follow Up&amp;lt;: You want them to immediately follow up on their point with a similar, related point. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Shift Directions: You want to shift into a new question or topic.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the three main types of buckets that I think about when posing new questions. The hard part is not really thinking of the questions, but asking them in the right way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-to-position-amp-execute-good-questions&quot;&gt;How to Position &amp;amp; Execute Good Questions:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to deliver high quality questions in the right way is to find the pause after which the speaker is finishing a threaded thought and is moving into a new moment. Don’t be afraid to insert yourself if you want to shift the conversation. The most important thing to remember is that it should be a discussion. How would you insert a comment or question into a conversation with your friend or family? Hopefully, by waiting for the right timing and by picking up on context clues based on the information they are feeding you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;5.) Know your acknowledgement words:&lt;/b&gt; Almost as important as asking good questions is listening to the responses your speaker gives and ackowledging important points. It likely seems trivial that this made it onto my top tips, but when you’re listening to a speaker tell a compelling story, or describe a fascinating thought on the market, nothing kills the mood than a misplaced comment or word. From what I’ve found, it’s best to keep things simple. Use words like “Yeah, Sure, Interesting, That’s really cool.” The more you try to interrupt, use long-winded and complicated phrases, or distract the listener from the speaker, the more drop-off you’re likely to get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;6.) Discussion &amp;amp; conversation vs. interview:&lt;/b&gt; After trying both models, I think there is a time and place for both types of podcasts. However, discussion podcasts tend to have higher listens, more shares, and are much easier to both conduct and listen to. A discussion makes things relaxed and in turn allows the speaker to talk about a subject in a way that most audiences never hear. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An interview can also lead to a great podcast, but most people freeze up when “interviewed” and tend to project prepared, static answers that do not lead to good pocast material. If you’re doing an interview it should be with somebody seasoned and who will be conducting the interview off the cuff (so that it feels more like a discussion) – even if the questions are curated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;7.) Don’t forget distribution:&lt;/b&gt; SoundCloud has become my go-to for podcasts because it is incredibly simple to setup and manage. Additionally, SoundCloud has great analytics at a pretty good price-point, which make it a great place to begin logging pods. However, despite this notion, it’s important to remember that there are many other notable channels for podcast distribution. In fact, if you don’t distribute to as many channels as possible, you run the risk of losing listeners. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this respect, I advise checking out the SoundCloud beta RSS program, which allows you to use your SoundCloud casts to distribute among most RSS aggregators, like iTunes, Stitcher, TuneIn, and Instacast. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start &lt;a href=&quot;http://help.soundcloud.com/customer/portal/articles/1197932-how-do-i-find-my-rss-feed-&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and fill out the application that you’ll see upon reading the first paragraph: RSS beta program &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/a/branchmetrics.io/forms/d/19VL22n_LS3MYJOxd54BwFo-a0LFTrnFQbe6kjb5SkyI/viewform&quot;&gt;application&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If approved, you can grab your RSS feed straight from SoundCloud and push a submission into &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/itunes/podcasts/specs.html#testing&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt; or other RSS aggregators. By far, this is the simplest way I have found to mass distribute podcasts with as little effort as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This list isn’t complete, but does capture an amateur’s start to podcasting. The best thing you can do for yourself as you start to curate and record podcasts is to think thoroughly about your intent, your audience, and yourself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What&lt;/b&gt; is the reason you’re making this podcast? What message or thoughts are you hoping to capture and convey? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Who&lt;/b&gt; is your audience; and who’s going to be most captivated by what you’re talking about? Speak to them! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;How&lt;/b&gt; are you coming across? Be self-aware. Think about how you ask questions, how you speak, what your voice sounds like and try to actively improve so that your listeners get the best experience you can deliver.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhay.com/podcast/2015/03/01/Podcasting-Takeaways-Part-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhay.com/podcast/2015/03/01/Podcasting-Takeaways-Part-1.html</guid>
        
        <category>Software</category>
        
        <category>Branch Metrics</category>
        
        <category>Personal Development</category>
        
        
        <category>podcast</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Big Announcement via Branch Metrics</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2015/02/26/branch-metrics-raises-15-million-for-its-smarter-mobile-deep-linking-technology/&quot;&gt;announcement of our Series A&lt;/a&gt; has been received with overwhelming support! I wrote about it in greater detail over on &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.branch.io/where-branch-is-headed/&quot;&gt;Branch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides our announcement, lots of people have asked us a simple question: How did Branch get started?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In another podcast with Branch Metrics, I sit down with the co-founding team at Branch Metrics to answer this question and talk about the future of both Branch and mobile deeplinking. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/193189451&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhay.com/branch/2015/02/27/A-Big-Announcement.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhay.com/branch/2015/02/27/A-Big-Announcement.html</guid>
        
        <category>Mobile</category>
        
        <category>Deeplinking</category>
        
        <category>Software</category>
        
        <category>Series A</category>
        
        <category>Venture Capital</category>
        
        <category>Personal Development</category>
        
        
        <category>branch</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A New Frontier: First Podcast @ Branch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An exciting career first happened earlier this week: I conducted my &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/branchmetrics&quot;&gt;first podcast&lt;/a&gt;. It seems trivial, but in fact, podcasting is not only a great way to learn, but a great way to dive into a company’s culture and help produce interesting, useful content. It’s also &lt;a href=&quot;http://digiday.com/platforms/podcasts-5-chars/&quot;&gt;growing&lt;/a&gt; in popularity at an insanely fast rate…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this first podcast, where I interview Branch CEO &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@alexaustin/just-keep-building-ca1e43df8e5a&quot;&gt;Alex Austin&lt;/a&gt;, we discuss mobile &amp;amp; deeplinking. What’s funny is that the podcast was an immense edification tool for myself; I hope it continues to serve this purpose not only for all the new partners and developers we work with, but also for incoming Branch employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/192190273&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a listen and &lt;a href=&quot;href=&amp;quot;http://austinhay.com/contact&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;give me feedback&lt;/a&gt;! What were things you enjoyed? What would you improve? This podcast series is only starting, so help me deliver the best, most compelling content you’d like to hear!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhay.com/podcast/2015/02/23/A-New-Frontier-Podcasts.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhay.com/podcast/2015/02/23/A-New-Frontier-Podcasts.html</guid>
        
        <category>Mobile</category>
        
        <category>Deeplinking</category>
        
        <category>Software</category>
        
        
        <category>podcast</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mobile Page Rank in Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/a16z/a16z-podcast-searching-for&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; titled “Searching for Mobile’s Own Pagerank” by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/balajis&quot;&gt;Balaji S.&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdixon.org/&quot;&gt;Chris Dixon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://ben-evans.com/&quot;&gt;Benedict Evans&lt;/a&gt; discuss the fact that a mobile pagerank really doesn’t exist and where the future of native vs. mobile apps might be headed. Many of the questions they pose center on mobile as an ecosystem that Evans’ likes to describe as a “swirling mass.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things may not have changed much in half a year, but I think it’s important to review their podcast and think about the questions that still linger on the industry’s mind with regard to finding a native page rank solution. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/141242781&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;original-podcast-notes&quot;&gt;Original Podcast Notes:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To save you some trouble, I’ve taken the liberty of curating a set of notes on the podcast. Enjoy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’re in the Pre-Page Rank era of mobile.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you look at the app store today it’s like looking at Yahoo in 1995.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No way to find the right things you want to use on the device.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;App stores are like Amazon – list everything that exists, but difficult to discover and explore.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pre-NetScape Phase as well: things are happening outside of the browser.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;How do we find, explore, and interact with content in the future?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There’s the app, webapp, card, url, messaging app etc., but it’s not yet well defined how to find the content you’re looking for. On the dev side, how you do you explore and engage customers within that?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chris Dixon: Nobody has invented the real page rank for mobile yet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is &lt;!-- --&gt;no HTML for native – no deeplinking through content, no analygous linking structure that you see on the web.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You don’t have a universal resource locator for every single piece of content with apps.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Even if you deeplink to content you still need to have the app.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The reason we had the web is because it was impossibly difficult to do anything else – it was too hard to get people to buy desktop software.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Smartphones are communication platforms that desktops never were.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The smartphone itself becomes a social platform – while the device fades into the background. You can see this in the disappearance of “Tech Specs” from most new Apple device intros. The focus is on the user experience, the beauty and more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not limited to the browser… you can do all other sorts of things.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pulling away from native apps. (Apple with health/cards)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You have to remember an app is just a view on top of an underlying data store.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Urbit – web links between pages… but how should we link between apps?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We shouldn’t really have to document an API for every app by utilizing the internal directory structure on the local phone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phones can be used as a distributed data center.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Links between applications based on data interces. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Large caches of local data – inversion of today’s model of access.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apple runs a full stack with integration based on fingerprinting, wireless, bluetooth etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google is trying to the opposite – lifting all its services into the cloud.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Language and player is less important than the mobile interaction – what will the icon on your homescreen look like? How did it get there? Did it appear automatically? Are there downnloads? Is it geo-traced? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deeplinking into apps fades away in this context.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who is it that is going to kill the native app? Apple.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google might try, but Apple will be the one who turns around and changes the infrastructure and platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;killer-questions-on-mobile-amp-deeplinking&quot;&gt;Killer Questions on Mobile &amp;amp; Deeplinking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, where does this leave us six months after a deep dive from the industry’s thought leaders into mobile and native? Not much further away from where we were then. As I began thinking about what’s changed, I was actually only able to come up with a new set of questions. Instead of answering questions, which I have no expertise to tackle, I will instead leave you with a new set of questions – hopefully to help you think about the changing target that is native page rank and the mobile industry as a whole. By virtue of my connection to &lt;a href=&quot;https://branch.io&quot;&gt;Branch&lt;/a&gt;, one of my key focuses in mobile is deeplinking. This definitely flavors my view of the mobile world:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why isn’t there a better way to search for apps on the app stores – both for Android and iOS?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Is this a universal developer pain point? Why?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How do you think deeplinking is going to help native apps evolve out of the pre-page rank era of mobile?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Why is deeplinking so much more than just the links?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How do you think deeplinking could solve the problem of not having a universal resource locator for every single piece of content with apps?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you think Apple is going to kill native apps?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you think native apps are going to die off in the same way that desktop software has?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you think deeplinking through the app stores and deeplinking app content really fades into the background when you think about mobile interaction from a very high level? How does Branch links fit into this ecosystem?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the questions on my mind as a technologist living in a world as unclear and swirling as Evans’ describes. For now, there are no good answers, but I feel confident knowing that perhaps &lt;a href=&quot;https://branch.io/features/&quot;&gt;links&lt;/a&gt; can get us there.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhay.com/branch/2015/02/21/Mobile-Page-Rank-in-Review.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhay.com/branch/2015/02/21/Mobile-Page-Rank-in-Review.html</guid>
        
        <category>Mobile</category>
        
        <category>Deeplinking</category>
        
        <category>Software</category>
        
        <category>Page Rank</category>
        
        <category>Native</category>
        
        
        <category>branch</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mobile Deeplinking Basics via Branch Metrics</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In this short article, oringinally &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.branch.io/mobile-deeplinking-basics/&quot;&gt;published on Branch&lt;/a&gt;, we dive into mobile deeplinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deep linking has been one of the most talked about trends in tech throughout the last year, but not everyone fully understands what deeplinking even is and how it can transform mobile. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deeplinking-in-context&quot;&gt;Deeplinking in Context&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile is taking over and deep linking is &lt;a href=&quot;http://readwrite.com/2015/01/29/deep-linking-button-urx-sdk-now-hot&quot;&gt;heating up&lt;/a&gt; alongside, as it promises to revolutionize UX and the way in which apps deliver content to users. Industry thought leaders have already started predicting how deeplinking may address the lack of true native page rank or how the end of the native app might be coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, news and media coverage focus on the promise of deep linking to provide HTTP-like functionality for mobile apps (more on this below!).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at Branch we look at all of these things and see a huge opportunity for developers to grow their native app audiences and bring about a fundamental change in the way people interact in the mobile ecosystem. So, digging deeper, what really are the benefits of deep linking? The technology helps app developers, marketers and users in a number of ways. Specifically, deep linking can:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.) Drive app install and conversion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.) Track organic growth channels, understand ad campaign impact on app numbers, and analyze K factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.) Supply dedicated user information &lt;u&gt;between&lt;/u&gt; web/mobile and &lt;u&gt;through&lt;/u&gt; app install.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.) Track and manage marketing campaign attribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5.) Linking analygous to HTTP providing a seamless way to interact with apps from links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6.) Allow mobile apps to work together, intuitively streamlining the process for developers - all of them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageleft&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://branch.io&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/branch/mobile-deeplinking-basics-1.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;font-style: italic; padding-top: 4%;&quot;&gt;
  With so many different benefits, it can be difficult to pick the deeplinking solution that does it all best. Branch links help app developers get the most out of deeplinks.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;This last point is particularly important: deep linking can allow your apps to have more exposure, higher installs and conversions, but most importantly, an easier, more intuitive integration with the mobile app ecosystem.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-a-deep-link&quot;&gt;What’s a Deep Link?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good thing about the internet is that there are many great resources that already exist on this subject. I’m in favor of you reading mine, but if it doesn’t quite suit your fancy, I’d recommend checking out &lt;a href=&quot;http://sarlitt.me/what-is-app-deep-linking/&quot;&gt;this other great read&lt;/a&gt; on Deep Linking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really, deeplinking begins with URIs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In programming, a URI (Uniform Resource Identifier) is just a string of characters to identify the name of a resource on a network. URIs allows users to identify and interact with the resource representation over a network using specific protocols. &lt;b&gt;The most common URI out there is the URL, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_resource_locator&quot;&gt;Uniform Resource Locator&lt;/a&gt; – or more simply, a web address.&lt;/b&gt; URIs are not not limited to just this. URIs can also be comprised of URNs (Uniform Resource Name). In practice a URN functions as a web resource’s “name” while the URL functions as its address. If you’re not sold on their differences, take a look &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/176264/whats-the-difference-between-a-uri-and-a-url&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a very high level a deeplink is just a hyperlink, or a special URI that routes to a resource deeper within a site’s hierarchy. It’s a hyperlink to an indexed or searchable page on a website other than the site’s home page. Generally, a website home page is at the top page in a site’s hierarchy and any other page outside of that is considered a “deep” link. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mobiledeeplinking.org/&quot;&gt;Mobile deep linking&lt;/a&gt; is really the type of “deep linking” that you’ve heard about among conversations with app and web developers. Mobile deep linking functions conceptually in the same way as web deep linking. As we discussed, deep links on the web are direct links to resources “deeper” within a site’s hierarchy. Today the term has come to encompass the methodology of routing to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techopedia.com/definition/27568/native-mobile-app&quot;&gt;native application&lt;/a&gt; via a hyperlink. In the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nngroup.com/articles/mobile-native-apps/&quot;&gt;war between web, native and hybrid applications&lt;/a&gt;, deep linking aims to make native applications more functional, more tightly integrated with the web, easier for users to operate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, again, &lt;b&gt;a mobile deep link&lt;/b&gt; is a URI that contains all the information needed to launch directly into an app or a particular location within an app instead of just launching the app home page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;deeplinking-examples&quot;&gt;Deeplinking Examples&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of web deep links, the underlying &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webopedia.com/TERM/H/HTTP.html&quot;&gt;HTTP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_resource_locator&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/a&gt; technologies allow for deep linking by default  – which is why you pretty much never hear the term deep linking reference anything but native app links these days. Native apps, however, do not have this same underlying core technology! It requires the apps to be configured to properly handle a URI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;In this way, as a URL is an address for a website on the internet, a URI for an app on a mobile device can function the same way IF deep linking technology is built into the app.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageright&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://branch.io/features/&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/branch/mobile-deeplinking-basics-2.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;font-style: italic; padding-top: 4%;&quot;&gt;
  Branch provides the universal links that the mobile and native app industry has wanted for years. Our links can help plug your app into the same type of deeplinking examples seen below.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some simple examples help demonstrate the point…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://mycoolwebsite.com&lt;/code&gt; This launches a website with the respective name on the internet! &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;twitter://&lt;/code&gt; This is the iOS URI to launch Twitter’s mobile app. Depending on what follows, this could link deep into the native app with tailored and specific content. If the user doesn’t own the app it could redirect them to the app store, or to the mobile website, or prompt the user for a choice. The possibilities are endless. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ftp://&lt;/code&gt; This launches the protocol to initiate a file transfer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;YouTube://&lt;/code&gt; This is the iOS URI to launch YouTube’s Mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-it-falls-apart&quot;&gt;Where it Falls Apart&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If deeplinks are so simple and intuitive, then what’s the problem? Why aren’t deeplinks ubiquitous yet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few reasons actually. First, deeplinking isn’t naturally built into the underlying framework of the native experience, like HTTP is built into the web. The only way to integrate deeplinking is through heavy lifting across all mobile platforms a developer supports (App Store, Play Store, Windows etc.) This is a huge barrier to entry for small developers hoping to have universal deeplinks into their app content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another big problem with deeplinking is that it can’t carry data through the app install process. Deeplinks don’t provide context about the user unless they have the app already installed on their device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple example demonstrates the point. If I pull out my phone and search for something – let’s just say “Branch Decor pinterest” ;) – then I am immediately brought to web results from Google. Let’s assume I’m interested in finding hits on Pinterest. I navigate to the first link, which properly captures these hits. You’ll notice that now I am routed to Pinterest’s mobile site. After a few seconds a popup recommend’s that I open the Pinterest App.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageright&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom:2%&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/branch/mobile-deeplinking-basics-3.png&quot; /&gt;

  &lt;p style=&quot;font-style: italic; padding-top: 4%;&quot;&gt;
  In this example, I am eventually trying to search for &quot;Branch Decor&quot; on Pinterest. Deeplinking currently can&#39;t pass data through the app install process. This leaves issues when new users are trying to access content on the native app from the web or mobile site. 
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point a few things are going on. First, Pinterest wants to drive me to the native app so that I can view the content in a more seamless way on the app they’ve spent loads of resources designing for native UX. So what happens when I click on the banner popup to navigate to the native app?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageright&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/branch/mobile-deeplinking-basics-4.png&quot; /&gt;

  &lt;p style=&quot;font-style: italic; padding-top: 4%;&quot;&gt;
	The first experience I have clicking on Pinterest&#39;s &quot;Open in App&quot; banner is an error message, then a slow redirect to the App Store. This is fundamentally a broken part of the way deeplinks are being deployed.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the current architecture of mobile, I am met with a “Cannot Open Page” error – this is because I had previously downloaded the app, so Pinterest thinks I still have the native app saved on my device. Once it realizes I don’t, it redirects me to the App Store where I am prompted to download the Pinterest App. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Okay. That’s not that big of a deal right? Well, actually, yes it is. In a world where &lt;a href=&quot;http://andrewchen.co/mobile-retention-benchmarks-for-2014-vs-2013-show-a-50-drop-in-d1-retention-guest-post/&quot;&gt;over 60% of users drop off less then 24 hours after download&lt;/a&gt; you’ve just provided the user’s first experience migrating to the native app as an error message. The old saying “First Impressions Matter” is still around for a reason. And in the world of deeplinking, this rings clearer than ever before.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how does the story end?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageright&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/branch/mobile-deeplinking-basics-5.png&quot; /&gt;

  &lt;p style=&quot;font-style: italic; padding-top: 4%;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;b&gt;Left:&lt;/b&gt; No Branch links are employed, so after this arduous and broken process, the user ends up logging in to Pinterest and is directed to the main homepage, wondering why they can&#39;t access the original content on which they clicked.&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;Right:&lt;/b&gt; Branch links are integrated. The user&#39;s data is passed through the install process. Not only did they not hit that pesky error message, but they were automatically, and quickly redirected to the correct App Store and fingerprinted for Pinterest. Now when they open up the app, they are brought right to the content they were looking for. No hacks, no gimmicks, no error messages. UX the way deeplinking intended.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, unfortunately, this is a tale of two deeplinking strategies. In one world, the (Right side of the figure) I would be met with the exact content that I had originally clicked on - “Twig Branch Decor”. But in reality, this is not how deeplinks are integrated. Instead of being brought to the content I wanted, or perhaps a personalized welcome screen, I am instead brought to a non-unique home page and left guessing how to access the content I originally wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;branch-solves-deeplinking-for-mobile&quot;&gt;Branch Solves Deeplinking for Mobile&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Branch fixes all of these problems and more. It eliminates the error caused by redirecting to the native app store, it automatically and quickly passes the user and attached data through the app store, and delivers a customized UX after the user downloads the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;To put it lightly, Branch deep links are mobile deeplinks on steroids. Our links provide all of the benefits and functionality described at the beginning of this piece and then some: automatic detection of the native app and redirect, flawless data flow &amp;amp; deeplink through the app store installation process, personalized app welcomes, a code-less referral program, the best attribution data collection and analytics dashboard on the market, and, of course, universal deeplinks to all in-app content. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://branch.io/case-studies/&quot;&gt;case studies&lt;/a&gt; dive deeper into how Branch is delivering on the best deeplink functionality available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Branch realizes all of the potential of deeplinking technology and makes it highly accessible.  Our links were created to maximize app growth &amp;amp; provide a tailored user experience. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;More importantly, this is just the tip of the iceberg for Branch links. As a company we are focused on serving those we care about most – developers. As such, we constantly build and test new features upon request. As developers need new features, we build them. It’s just that simple.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageleft&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://branch.io/features/&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/branch/mobile-deeplinking-basics-6.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;font-style: italic; padding-top: 4%;&quot;&gt;
  HotelTonight uses Branch links to drive installs, increase conversions, and provide the best possible UX to its app users. What&#39;s stopping you from doing the same?
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;coming-full-circle-why-mobile-deep-linking-matters&quot;&gt;Coming Full Circle: Why Mobile Deep Linking Matters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The greatest benefit of mobile deep linking is the fact that it allows app developers &amp;amp; their marketing teams to bring users directly into a very specific location within the app with a dedicated link, or provide a customized welcome to the app. Deep linking can stop the trend of platforms losing their native users to the web, mobile or just in terms of straight app retention. It can automatically detect the native experience and redirect users accordingly, just as deep links have done &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nngroup.com/articles/deep-linking-is-good-linking/&quot;&gt;for the web&lt;/a&gt;. And this is just the start. Deep linking can create a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.appsflyer.com/deep-linking-now-time-mobile-search-ads/&quot;&gt;better native search&lt;/a&gt;, increase &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.facebook.com/docs/ads-for-apps/mobile-app-ads-engagement&quot;&gt;ad sales&lt;/a&gt;, drive &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.superbcrew.com/branchmetrics-helps-you-get-all-the-data-need-for-your-customer-acquisition-strategy/&quot;&gt;app conversion and organic growth channels&lt;/a&gt;, and overall create a better UX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In turn, this type of technology has the potential to increase the ad market across mobile and web, better manage download traffic, bring context to the core content of an app, drive conversions, and ultimately, index all the content on an app for a more intuitive and functional search. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’ve experienced the pains of app growth without deep linking or if you’ve just heard the term flung around at the lunch table, deep linking is worth knowing about and understanding. If &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/a16z/a16z-podcast-mobile-is-eating-the-world-and-apple-is-gobbling-fastest&quot;&gt;mobile is eating the world&lt;/a&gt; then deep linking is at the head of the table.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhay.com/branch/2015/02/18/Mobile-Deeplinking-Basics.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhay.com/branch/2015/02/18/Mobile-Deeplinking-Basics.html</guid>
        
        <category>Mobile</category>
        
        <category>Deeplinking</category>
        
        <category>Software</category>
        
        <category>App Development</category>
        
        <category>Branch Metrics</category>
        
        
        <category>branch</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lessons From Accenture</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was grinding through the second year of my grad programs I had no idea what I wanted to do. Strangely enough, graduate school had actually opened the possibilities for my career trajectory rather than closed doors or pushed me into a niche field. I felt empowered to pursue science, technology, business, and programming, but I didn’t know where to start. Accenture provided me with a phenomenal launchpad to figure this out. It gave me time to discover where my technical skills aligned most with business needs, and through the months that I worked there, I discovered many of the “rules of the road” for operating at Fortune 500 companies. 
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;imageleft&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogs/lessons-from-accenture-1.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a huge fan of simple rules so that’s how I’m going to break down my reflections from Accenture. The concept of &lt;a href=&quot;/pdfs/Eisenhardt-StrategyAsSimpleRules.pdf&quot;&gt;simple rules&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://profiles.stanford.edu/kathleen-eisenhardt&quot;&gt;Dr. Kathleen Eisenhardt&lt;/a&gt; is that when business gets complicated, stick to some basic guiding rules that define your strategy. I love the principle of simple rules so much that now I try to glean simple rules from all the different chapters in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, my time at Accenture felt complicated. Everyday it seemed like I was served up new lessons, some more nuanced than others. Looking back, however, I found it hard to take away concrete operating lessons – but luckily some simple rules have proved to be clarifying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;simple-rules-from-accenture&quot;&gt;Simple Rules from Accenture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;1.) It’s all about the people.&lt;/b&gt; It doesn’t get much simpler than this. Like any mega organization of its kinda, Accenture has a wide variety of people. One thing that I took away from navigating this type of ecosystem is that you have to surround yourself with the people you hope to become. Those who left the biggest impression on me were the ones that were smart, open-minded, driven, focused, thoughtful and empathetic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best people were not just the smartest either, but they were the ones who had a deep fascination and love of learning and weren’t afraid to show it. More importantly, they left their egos at the door and were willing to recognize, cherish and nourish talent when they came across it. In the future, these are the types of people I hope to surround myself by. Life is too short to spend time with others who aren’t going to push you to develop and grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageright-1&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;/personal%20development/2015/01/20/Reflections-From-SETS.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/lessons-from-accenture-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	I visited Accenture in Bangalore on a trip to India with Stanford to study business, entrepreneurship and innovation during the summer of 2014.
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2.) Don’t pick something that feels comfortable.&lt;/b&gt; This idea hit me early on when I started. After training for two weeks in Chicago at ACN’s center in St. Charles, IL, I came home hungry to dive into my first project. I was taken back, however, to find that few of the projects open fit my background, interests, or technical skills. Eager to learn and to grow, I found one that fit and ran with it. In hindsight this may not have been the best move for me personally, but from one perspective, I learned so much from immersing myself in a field that was uncomfortable – where I didn’t have all the answers or skills yet and where I was challenged to learn more. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of sitting on the bench hoping for the perfect opportunity to come along, I was swimming in a sea of analyst hurt, working my butt off, but growing from the experience. This isn’t to say this strategy is for everyone. It certainly caused some problems for me down the road when I craved a better outlet for math and analytics. But in the short run, I rapidly grew from the experience. In your career and in life, don’t be afraid to get uncomfortable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;3.) Become a strategist AND an operator, not just one or the other.&lt;/b&gt; This is another one of those “Duh” lessons, but it really gets underlooked. When I came out of school I had travelled the road of Management Consulting. The interviews with McKinsey, Bain, BCG, the case prep from Victor Cheng, the countless hours thinking about markets, their trends, and profitability problems. Everyone wanted to be in strategy and nobody wanted to be in operations because it wasn’t sexy or fun. In reality, operations proved to be more valuable and meaningful to my professional development. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Operators are those people who can take strategy and translation it into action. They are the ones with a bias for action, a hunger for process, and a mentality of “get shit done.” Strategy is fun and incredibly intellectually stimulating, but don’t let that convince you that there’s not a place in everyone’s toolbelt for operations. Be a strategist and an operator. Plan and perform. Think about tough problems and then, get your hands dirty and solve them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;4.) Challenge the status quo – understand the impact, but don’t be afraid of it.&lt;/b&gt; This is really summed up by one simple question in the words of my greatest mentor: do you care more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2010/08/true-leaders-are-also-managers/&quot;&gt;doing things right or doing the right thing?&lt;/a&gt; Not only will the answer to this question will tell you a lot about yourself, but it will paint a path to professional development. In my own life, I have always tried to be a straight-shooter and somebody who builds things for a reason. I like to know the purpose behind a process or decision and I am comfortable admitting when I’m wrong and changing things that are broken or inefficient. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a large corporation there will be many opportunities to find broken things. Good companies, good leaders, good bosses, and good people will all encourage and embrace those who call out problems with the way things are done – whether its business decisions, operations, daily processes, or even the way events are planned. But not every organization will have these people and this type of culture. A true test of professional strength and willpower will be when you decide how to handle challenging the status quo when there’s realy pushback. I’m not telling you to start a fire, but I am telling you that if you want to learn to do the right thing, this is a good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wrap-up&quot;&gt;Wrap Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day Accenture was a great place to start my career and I am unbelievably thankful to the people and mentors that encouraged me and helped me succeed. The most important part of this whole process has been reflection. Taking the time to think about the things that went well and those that didn’t has given me insight into my day-to-day professional needs as well as the areas that I have room for personal improvement. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I can recommend only one thing for those moving on to new careers it is that you take the time to digest the greatest lessons from your employer. Think about them, reflect, write them down and internalize them. When life gets complicated, keep things simple. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhay.com/personal%20development/2015/02/15/Lessons-From-Accenture.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhay.com/personal%20development/2015/02/15/Lessons-From-Accenture.html</guid>
        
        <category>Reflection</category>
        
        <category>Accenture</category>
        
        <category>Awareness</category>
        
        <category>Self development</category>
        
        <category>Life lessons</category>
        
        
        <category>personal development</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Wild Ride</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s rare that you wake up wondering to yourself…“Was that all a dream?” The week has certainly felt that way. I learned about &lt;a href=&quot;https://branch.io/&quot;&gt;Branch Metrics&lt;/a&gt; less than three weeks ago. Their product, a simple drop in SDK that finally lets app developers track, monitor and manage their users using deep linking, is going to disrupt the mobile industry. It wasn’t just their technology that took my breath away, their team of founders is one of the most thoughtful and inspiring groups of people I have ever met. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://branch.io&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;imageleft-1&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogs/wild-ride-1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In grad school at Stanford I took a number of business classes where I learned the importance in surrounding yourself by the brightest and best people you can find. The goal in achieving professional success and happiness was about doing something you’re passionate about and diving in with people who are going to challenge you and make you a better person. I absolutely found these types of great people and a real opportunity to grow at &lt;a href=&quot;http://branch.io&quot;&gt;Branch&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The added bonus of the opportunity to work for Branch is the fact that I’m going to be in a role that will truly utilize my skills and will help me grow both my business acumen and technical abilities. With a small team of 12, Branch is growing rapdily in the next few months and needs people who can manage several domains of expertise, who are comfortable with sales and business intelligence, but also who aren’t afraid of code. They need people who are willing to take risks, use data to drive business decisions, possibly &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/Am-I-set-up-for-slower-growth-if-more-experienced-execs-are-hired-above-me-at-fast-growing-company/answer/Auren-Hoffman?ref=fb&quot;&gt;fail&lt;/a&gt; along the way, but ultimately grow from the experience. More specifically, they want somebody with a technical background, business understanding, and a love of technology. When I heard this I felt it was a match made in heaven, and I couldn’t have been more excited to join.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If all this wasn’t enough to convince me, their co-founder CEO, Alex Austin  – yes, it is comically fitting that we have inverse names – left me with one honest promise: A wild ride. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve decided to join the team at Branch Metrics in Palo Alto, and close my chapter at Accenture. Check out their &lt;a href=&quot;https://branch.io/contextual-deep-links/&quot;&gt;product&lt;/a&gt;, which I also write about more in the future. I hope you will follow &amp;amp; support me in this exciting new journey!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhay.com/personal%20development/2015/02/12/A-Wild-Ride.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhay.com/personal%20development/2015/02/12/A-Wild-Ride.html</guid>
        
        <category>Branch Metrics</category>
        
        <category>Professional Development</category>
        
        <category>Reflection</category>
        
        <category>Self development</category>
        
        
        <category>personal development</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is Deep Linking?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Deep linking has been one of the most talked about trends in tech throughout the last year, but not everyone fully understands what it is and how it can transform mobile. Look no further – this is a quick guide on what you need to know about mobile deep linking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-current-landscape&quot;&gt;The Current Landscape&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;float: right; margin: 2%; padding-right: 3%; margin-top: 0;&quot; width=&quot;35%&quot; height=&quot;auto&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/188674648&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it’s best to start with the current landscape. Mobile is taking over, and deep linking is &lt;a href=&quot;http://readwrite.com/2015/01/29/deep-linking-button-urx-sdk-now-hot&quot;&gt;heating up&lt;/a&gt; alongside as it promises to revolutionize UX and the way in which apps deliver content to users. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most stories focus on the promise of deep linking to provide HTTP-like functionality for mobile apps (more on this below!). Meanwhile, companies are rapidly materializing to deliver on this potential: &lt;a href=&quot;http://branch.io&quot;&gt;Branch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.urx.com&quot;&gt;URX&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trywildcard.com/&quot;&gt;Wildcard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usebutton.com/&quot;&gt;Button&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://deeplink.me/&quot;&gt;Deeplink.me&lt;/a&gt; to name a few. These new marketing and developer-centric startups are all chasing the future of how &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/nathaniel-cahners-hindman/a-deep-link-deep-dive-urx-wildcard-button-deeplinkme-demo-the-future-of-mobile_b_6449214.html&quot;&gt;deeplinks will define the future app ecosytem and user experience&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What really are the benefits of deep linking? The technology helps app developers, marketers and users in a number of ways. Specifically, deep linking can:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageleft-1&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://branch.io&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/what-is-deep-linking-1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	Branch Metrics is one deep linking startup that is delivering on the promises of the technology. They&#39;ve built a custom SDK and API that provides a way for developers to easily integrate deep linking into their core app, and build robust referral &amp;amp; conversion platforms. 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.) Drive app install and conversion - &lt;a href=&quot;http://branch.io&quot;&gt;Branch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.urx.com&quot;&gt;URX&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usebutton.com/&quot;&gt;Button&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://deeplink.me/&quot;&gt;Deeplink.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.) Track organic growth channels, understand ad campaign impact on app numbers, and analyze K factors - only &lt;a href=&quot;http://branch.io&quot;&gt;Branch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.) Supply dedicated user information &lt;u&gt;between&lt;/u&gt; web/mobile and &lt;u&gt;through&lt;/u&gt; app install. This includes actions between apps from users - only &lt;a href=&quot;http://branch.io&quot;&gt;Branch&lt;/a&gt;, but most deep linking vendors provide UX connectivity for between-app interactions, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.urx.com&quot;&gt;URX&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usebutton.com/&quot;&gt;Button&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trywildcard.com/&quot;&gt;Wildcard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://deeplink.me/&quot;&gt;Deeplink.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.) Linking analygous to HTTP providing a seamless way to interact with apps from links - &lt;a href=&quot;http://branch.io&quot;&gt;Branch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.urx.com&quot;&gt;URX&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trywildcard.com/&quot;&gt;Wildcard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usebutton.com/&quot;&gt;Button&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://deeplink.me/&quot;&gt;Deeplink.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5.) Allow mobile apps to work together, intuitively streamlining the process for developers - all of them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;This last point is the most salient one: deep linking can allow your apps to have more exposure, higher installs and conversions, but most importantly, an easier, more intuitive integration with the mobile app ecosystem.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-a-deep-link&quot;&gt;What is a Deep Link?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good thing about the internet is that there are many great resources that already exist on this subject. I’m in favor of you reading mine, but if it doesn’t quite suit your fancy, I’d recommend checking out &lt;a href=&quot;http://sarlitt.me/what-is-app-deep-linking/&quot;&gt;this other great read&lt;/a&gt; on Deep Linking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve covered the landscape of deep linking and you have an idea of the technology’s benefits, it’s time to dive into how it works – beginning with URIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;uris-are-the-foundation-of-deep-linking&quot;&gt;URI’s are the Foundation of Deep Linking&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In programming, a URI (Uniform Resource Identifier) is just a string of characters to identify the name of a resource on a network. URIs allows users to identify and interact with the resource representation over a network using specific protocols. &lt;b&gt;The most common URI out there is the URL, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_resource_locator&quot;&gt;Uniform Resource Locator&lt;/a&gt; – or more simply, a web address.&lt;/b&gt; URIs are not not limited to just this. URIs can also be comprised of URNs (Uniform Resource Name). In practice a URN functions as a web resource’s “name” while the URL functions as its address. If you’re not sold on their differences, take a look &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/176264/whats-the-difference-between-a-uri-and-a-url&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageleft&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://sarlitt.me/what-is-app-deep-linking/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/what-is-deep-linking-2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	This simple visual from Michael Sarlitt shows the primary differences between web and native apps. Check out his full post for a developer focused intro to deep linking. 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a very high level a deep link is just a hyperlink, or a special URI that routes to a resource deeper within a site’s hierarchy. It’s a hyperlink to an indexed or searchable page on a website other than the site’s home page. Generally, a website home page is at the top page in a site’s hierarchy and any other page outside of that is considered a “deep” link. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mobiledeeplinking.org/&quot;&gt;Mobile deep linking&lt;/a&gt; is really the type of “deep linking” that you’ve heard about among conversations with app and web developers. Mobile deep liking functions conceptually in the same way as web deep linking. As we discussed, deep links on the web are direct links to resources “deeper” within a site’s hierarchy. Today the term has come to encompass the methodology of routing to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techopedia.com/definition/27568/native-mobile-app&quot;&gt;native application&lt;/a&gt; via a hyperlink. In the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nngroup.com/articles/mobile-native-apps/&quot;&gt;war between web, native and hybrid applications&lt;/a&gt;, deep linking aims to make native applications more functional, more tightly integrated with the web, easier for users to operate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, again, &lt;b&gt;a mobile deep link is just a URI that contains all the information needed to launch directly into an app or a particular location within an app instead of just launching the app home page.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;examples-of-deep-links&quot;&gt;Examples of Deep Links&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of web deep links, the underlying &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webopedia.com/TERM/H/HTTP.html&quot;&gt;HTTP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_resource_locator&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/a&gt; technologies allow for deep linking by default  – which is why you pretty much never hear the term deep linking reference anything but native app links these days. Native mobile apps, however, do not have this same underlying core technology! It requires the apps to be configured to properly handle a URI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;In this way, as a URL is an address for a website on the internet, a URI for an app on a mobile device can function the same way IF deep linking technology is built into the app.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some simple examples help demonstrate the point…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://mycoolwebsite.com&lt;/code&gt; This launches a website with the respective name on the internet! &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;twitter://&lt;/code&gt; This is the iOS URI to launch Twitter’s mobile app. Depending on what follows, this could link deep into the native app with tailored and specific content. If the user doesn’t own the app it could redirect them to the app store, or to the mobile website, or prompt the user for a choice. The possibilities are endless. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ftp://&lt;/code&gt; This launches the protocol to initiate a file transfer&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;YouTube://&lt;/code&gt; This is the iOS URI to launch YouTube’s Mobile app&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;imageright&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://sarlitt.me/what-is-app-deep-linking/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogs/what-is-deep-linking-3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	This is another awesome visual from Michael Sarlitt showing how deep links can redirect users to highly specific in-app content from any ad, but especially mobile and web ads. Check out his post on deeplinking for a more developer-focused overview. If you&#39;re interested in implementing this type of behavior check out the options up top. Currently &lt;a href=&quot;http://branch.io&quot;&gt;Branch Metrics&lt;/a&gt; seems like the best option to handle this type of action and they pass data through install as well, which opens up a whole world of possibilities for UX.
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully deep linking is starting to become more clear!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;back-to-the-point-why-mobile-deep-linking-matters&quot;&gt;Back to the Point: Why Mobile Deep Linking Matters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The greatest benefit of mobile deep linking is the fact that it allows app developers &amp;amp; their marketing teams to bring users directly into a very specific location within the app with a dedicated link. Deep linking can stop the trend of platforms losing their mobile users to the web. It can automatically detect the native experience and redirect users accordingly, just as deep links have done &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nngroup.com/articles/deep-linking-is-good-linking/&quot;&gt;for the web&lt;/a&gt;. And this is just the start. Deep linking can create a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.appsflyer.com/deep-linking-now-time-mobile-search-ads/&quot;&gt;better native search&lt;/a&gt;, increase &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.facebook.com/docs/ads-for-apps/mobile-app-ads-engagement&quot;&gt;ad sales&lt;/a&gt;, drive &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.superbcrew.com/branchmetrics-helps-you-get-all-the-data-need-for-your-customer-acquisition-strategy/&quot;&gt;app conversion and organic growth channels&lt;/a&gt;, and overall create a better UX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In turn this type of technology has the potential to increase the ad market across mobile and web, better manage download traffic, bring context to the core content of an app, drive conversions, and ultimately, index all the content on an app for a more intuitive and functional search. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’ve experienced the pains of app growth without deep linking or if you’ve just heard the term flung around at the lunch table, deep linking is worth knowing about and understanding. If &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/a16z/a16z-podcast-mobile-is-eating-the-world-and-apple-is-gobbling-fastest&quot;&gt;mobile is eating the world&lt;/a&gt; then deep linking is at the head of the table.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhay.com/coding/2015/02/06/What-is-Deep-Linking.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhay.com/coding/2015/02/06/What-is-Deep-Linking.html</guid>
        
        <category>Deep Linking</category>
        
        <category>Software</category>
        
        <category>Web-development</category>
        
        <category>Technology</category>
        
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
